<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://www.jboss.org/blogs.html</id>
    <title>JBoss Blogs</title>
    <updated>2021-12-13T18:25:30.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jboss.org/blogs.html"/>
    <subtitle>aggregation of various JBoss blogs</subtitle>
    <icon>https://www.jboss.org/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KIE & Log4j2 exploit CVE-2021-44228]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/kie-log4j2-exploit-cve-2021-44228.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/kie-log4j2-exploit-cve-2021-44228.html"/>
        <updated>2021-12-13T18:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[2.x is a widely used Java logging framework. Unfortunately a few days ago it has been exposed to an important (“Log4Shell”, CVE-2021-44228).   The whole KIE ecosystem (Kogito, Drools, OptaPlanner and jBPM) moved to , a different logging facade with Logback as default implementation, a few years ago and it is therefore not vulnerable by CVE-2021-44228. Accordingly, our recommendation is to ensure your applications are updated to the latest community versions (at the time of writing, Drools, jBPM, KIE Workbench/Business Central and KIE Server 7.62.0.Final, Kogito 1.14.1.Final, Optaplanner 8.14.0.Final).  Therefore if you’re using KIE projects as libraries in your projects you are not affected by this problem. Note that the , only declares the Log4j2 dependency management without actually depending on it. Dashbuilder is a monitoring component included in Business Central. We are about to just in case.  In case you’re declaring and/or using Log4j2 dependency in your own KIE projects, please make sure to upgrade Log4j2 as soon as possible to version 2.15.0 which solves this problem.   We invite you to monitor this blog post, which will be updated in case of any future additional findings.  Further readings:  Update note: We found that Dashbuilder brought in log4j-core as a transitive dependency from the module uberfire-metadata-backend-elasticsearch and it has been . The latest version of KIE Workbench/Business Central containing it was 7.46.0.Final.  The post appeared first on .  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Mario Fusco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to handle CVE-2021-44228 in Java applications]]></title>
        <id>http://www.mastertheboss.com/jbossas/jboss-log/how-to-handle-cve-2021-44228-in-java-applications/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-to-handle-cve-2021-44228-in-java-applications</id>
        <link href="http://www.mastertheboss.com/jbossas/jboss-log/how-to-handle-cve-2021-44228-in-java-applications/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-to-handle-cve-2021-44228-in-java-applications"/>
        <updated>2021-12-13T17:14:36.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[This short articles discussed the recent flaw in Log4j2 library which affects some recent versions of this opensource library. Let’s see how to perform checks and mitigation actions if your Java applications are using a flawed Log4j2 version. As discussed in this CVE there is a flaw in certain Log4j2 versions: From 2.0.0 to version ...  The post appeared first on .]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>F.Marchioni</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Infinispan and Log4j CVE-2021-44228]]></title>
        <id>https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/12/13/infinispan-log4j-cve-releases</id>
        <link href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/12/13/infinispan-log4j-cve-releases"/>
        <updated>2021-12-13T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Infinispan community,  We’ve just released , and to address the . Additionally, we have released upgraded versions of the Infinispan Operator to match the server versions: 2.2.2.Final for Infinispan 13.0 and 2.1.6.Final for Infinispan 12.1. Please upgrade as soon as you can. Refer to our for versions.   WHAT’S AFFECTED  We include log4j-core in our server distributions, including the . We are fixing the issue by upgrading to Log4J 2.15.0.   MITIGATION STRATEGIES  If you cannot upgrade, there are a several you can apply. But upgrading is always the best solution.]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Tristan Tarrant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse Vert.x and Log4j 2 CVE-2021-44228]]></title>
        <id>https://vertx.io/blog/CVE-2021-44228</id>
        <link href="https://vertx.io/blog/CVE-2021-44228"/>
        <updated>2021-12-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[A recent [CVE-2021-44228](https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2021-44228) has been disclosed that affects the Log4j 2 library. The Vert.x project can *optionally* use this library for logging but *does not ship* this library and therefore is not affected by this CVE.]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Julien Viet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using RESTEasy Tracing Feature With Feature Pack In WildFly]]></title>
        <id>https://resteasy.github.io/2021/12/13/tracing-feature/</id>
        <link href="https://resteasy.github.io/2021/12/13/tracing-feature/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WildFly Impact of the Apache Log4j Security Vulnerabilities]]></title>
        <id>https://wildfly.org//news/2021/12/13/Log4j-CVEs/</id>
        <link href="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/12/13/Log4j-CVEs/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[WildFly users are of course interested in the impact of the recently disclosed security vulnerabilities related to Apache Log4j. On Friday the @WildFlyAS Twitter account . In this post I want to provide further details, information on how users who package the log4j-core artifact in their WildFly application deployments can mitigate the risk, and provide information on how the affects WildFly.   CVE-2021-44228  is a critical impact zero-day vulnerability in the Apache Log4j log4j-core library whereby a remote attacker who can control log messages or log message parameters can execute arbitrary code on a server via a JNDI lookup.  I won’t get into the technical details of the exploit here; instead I refer you to .  This vulnerability is in code in the Log4j 2 org.apache.logging.log4j:log4j-core artifact. The WildFly application server project does not ship this artifact, and it never has. So, the only way an application running on WildFly would be vulnerable to the CVE-2021-44228 vulnerability is if the log4j-core artifact has been added to the server installation, either via a user-provided JBoss Modules module, or more likely by packaging log4j-core in an application deployment artifact.  Note that since WildFly 22, WildFly does ship the Log4j 2 org.apache.logging.log4j:log4j-api artifact, and up to WildFly 26.0.0.Beta1 the version of that artifact matches the CVE-2021-44228 CPE. However, the log4j-api artifact does not contain the vulnerable code.. Note that even though the artifact on WildFly 26.0.0.Beta1 does not have the vulnerability, to help avoid confusion the upcoming 26.0.0.Final release will move to the 2.15.0 version of the artifact, which does not match the CVE-2021-44228 CPE.   MITIGATION STRATEGIES  If your application does include the log4j-core artifact, the following are steps you can take to mitigate any vulnerability:  SET FORMATMSGNOLOOKUPS=TRUE  Update the $WILDFLY_HOME/bin/standalone.conf or $WILDFLY_HOME/bin/domain.conf file (or, for Windows users, the .bat or .ps1 variants of those) to add -Dlog4j2.formatMsgNoLookups=true to the value of the JAVA_OPTS environment variable. (Which file you update depends on whether you are running a standalone server or a domain mode host.)  This is the quickest mitigation, but as soon as you can you should also…  UPGRADE LOG4J-CORE TO THE 2.15.0 OR LATER RELEASE  The Apache Log4j project has that fixes the flaw. If you are packaging log4j-core in your application we recommend updating your deployment artifact to 2.15.0 or later as soon as possible.  Note that I’ve seen user reports that upgrading to 2.15.0 in a deployment is problematic when the container is providing an earlier release of the log4j-api artifact. This should not be a problem if you are following the . If you are packaging log4j-core, you should exclude any module dependency on the log4-api provided by WildFly and instead package log4j-api in your deployment.   CVE-2021-4104  Recently Red Hat , in this case Log4j 1. They rated the impact of this vulnerability as "Moderate impact", unlike their which was rated as "Critical impact". (For more on the difference between "Critical" and "Moderate", see .)  CVE-2021-4104 has some surface similarity to CVE-2021-44228, in that both relate to a logging library doing a JNDI lookup, with a risk that that library could be fooled into doing a lookup and deserialization of content from an untrustworthy source. In the CVE-2021-4104 case the lookups can be performed by the org.apache.log4j.net.JMSAppender class, a class that is used if an application configures a log appender meant to write to an external JMS topic. The JMSAppender lookup is quite different from the CVE-2021-44228 one though, in that the name being looked up is meant to be of a string provided as part of the appender’s configuration, not one that is incorporated in a log message. It is significantly easier to get a server to inject a malicious string into a log message than it is to inject one into the container configuration. The latter would typically require some sort of privileged access to the server. This increased difficulty of exploit is one of the when deciding the severity of a vulnerability.  WildFly does not ship Apache Log4j 1 itself, but the org.jboss.logmanager:log4j-jboss-logmanager artifact we ship shades the Log4j 1 classes, including JMSAppender. JMSAppender has been present in WildFly or JBoss AS at least as far back as JBoss AS 7.1, and probably much farther.  However, our attempts to configure WildFly to use the JMSAppender have been unsuccessful, failing before the JMSAppender code reaches a point where it does any JNDI lookup. This is because the JBoss Modules module that packages org.jboss.logmanager:log4j-jboss-logmanager does not include a dependency on the module that provides the javax.naming package, resulting in a ClassNotFoundException if the class is used. So at this point we don’t see an exploit involving normal modular use of the org.jboss.logmanager:log4j-jboss-logmanager artifact we ship. Exploits would likely require the use of reflection.  If you package Apache Log4j 1 in your application, be careful not to expose to untrusted callers any mechanism that would allow them to access the JMSAppender class or configure instances of it. Which is the right thing to do in general! Running with the JVM security manager enabled is another way to defend against attacks based on getting your application to make unexpected calls to external systems.  If you have any questions about any of the above, I encourage you to ask on the .  Best regards,  Brian]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Stansberry</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keycloak 15.1.0 released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.keycloak.org/2021/12/keycloak-1510-released</id>
        <link href="https://www.keycloak.org/2021/12/keycloak-1510-released"/>
        <updated>2021-12-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[To download the release go to .   HIGHLIGHTS   QUARKUS DISTRIBUTION PREVIEW  Without comparison the biggest highlight of this release is all the improvements that have been made to the Quarkus distribution. So many in fact, that it will be hard to list them all.  The CLI has been polished to hell and back, and we believe it now provides a very simple and convenient approach to configuring and running Keycloak. It’s almost so simple that documentation shouldn’t be needed.  To get started, just unpack the distribution, then type bin/kc.[sh|bat] -h to discover awesomeness!  That doesn’t mean we don’t plan to provide documentation for configuring Keycloak, but it didn’t quite make it this time around. In lack of documentation expect a blog post to follow the release introducing all the changes to the Quarkus distribution, as well as an overview on how to use it.  We are rapidly moving towards making the Quarkus distribution our default distribution, and will soon deprecate the WildFly distribution. With this in mind it is important that as many people as possible give it a test-run and provide us with feedback if you find any usability issues, are not able to configure something with it, or if you discover any bugs.  We’d love to hear your thoughts and get your feedback in !   NEW ADMIN CONSOLE PREVIEW  The new admin console is shaping up really nicely, and a preview is included in the main distribution. It is not quite feature complete yet, but there are still loads of things to try out.   WILDFLY UPDATE  Upgrading from WildFly 23 to WildFly 25 has taken a lot longer than we would have liked. We’re still working hard on this and are hoping to release Keycloak 16 as soon as possible with the upgrade, but as we wanted to get the updates to the Quarkus distribution out there we are doing this release in the meantime.   WILDFLY ADAPTER DEPRECATION  In WildFly 25 there is now excellent native OpenID Connect support without the need for the Keycloak adapter. With this in mind we are deprecating our WildFly adapter and will not support WildFly 25, but it will be around for a while for older WildFly versions and Red Hat JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 7.y.   SPRING SECURITY AND BOOT ADAPTER DEPRECATION  A long time ago, with Spring Security 5.0, there is now native support for OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect in Spring. With this in mind now is the time to start deprecating our Spring Boot and Security adapters.   OPENID CONNECT FRONT-CHANNEL LOGOUT SUPPORT  Keycloak now supports .  For more details, take a look at .  Thanks to for the contribution.   DEPRECATED FEATURES IN THE KEYCLOAK OPERATOR  With this release, we have deprecated and/or marked as unsupported some features in the Keycloak Operator. This concerns the Backup CRD and the operator managed Postgres Database. For more details, please see the .   ALL RESOLVED ISSUES  The full list of resolved issues are available in   UPGRADING  Before you upgrade remember to backup your database and check the for anything that may have changed.]]></content>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quarkus 2.5.2.Final released - Maintenance release]]></title>
        <id>https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-5-2-final-released/</id>
        <link href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-5-2-final-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[We just released Quarkus 2.5.2.Final, a maintenance release for our 2.5 release train containing bugfixes and documentation improvements. It is a safe upgrade for anyone already using 2.5. If you are not using 2.5 already, please refer to the 2.5 migration guide. Full changelog You can get the full changelog...]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Guillaume Smet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DMN example application with Quarkus]]></title>
        <id>http://www.mastertheboss.com/bpm/kogito/dmn-example-application-with-quarkus/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=dmn-example-application-with-quarkus</id>
        <link href="http://www.mastertheboss.com/bpm/kogito/dmn-example-application-with-quarkus/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=dmn-example-application-with-quarkus"/>
        <updated>2021-12-09T17:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[In our first tutorial about DMN – Getting started with Decision Models (DMN) – we have covered the foundation of Decision Models and the key components in it. In this follow up article we will design and create an example application which exposes a simple Decision Model through Quarkus REST Services. Designing the Decision Model ...  The post appeared first on .]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>F.Marchioni</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smart Scroll for BPMN/DMN Editors]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/smart-scroll-for-bpmn-admn-editors.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/smart-scroll-for-bpmn-admn-editors.html"/>
        <updated>2021-12-09T15:21:06.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[INTRODUCING SMART SCROLL  Creating and managing BPMN/DMN resources can be a daunting task. Projects can come in many shapes and sizes and with varying levels of complexity. Consequently, being able to locate and identify nodes is of utmost importance. Focusing on easing the load of such demands, we introduce Smart Scroll for BPMN/DMN editors. Available for , this new feature enables scroll by dragging a canvas element close to a border. With it, node placement becomes a more natural task.   USING SMART SCROLL  To activate it, drag any canvas element (e.g., all nodes, bend points, and connection points) closer to the canvas border. Then, while still holding the mouse drag button, cease mouse movement. As a result, scrolling starts in the desired direction. Mind you, due to canvas limitations, scrolling beyond the origin limit (depicted by the dashed lines) is not possible.  First to the right, then to the left – Smart Scroll activation No scrolling beyond canvas origin limit – Smart Scroll limits Canvas origin limits depiction in detail – Smart Scroll limits   SCROLL BAR IMPROVEMENTS  By itself, the Smart Scroll already proves valuable. But, to stand out and give that "just right" feeling, other changes were necessary. Next, we discuss them and show a side-by-side comparison of old vs. new to highlight the differences.  The first change is real-time updates. In sum, there is no need to end element drag for the scrollbar to update. It happens as soon as there is drag movement. In the comparison below, pay attention to the scroll bar at the bottom.  Drag end triggers scroll bar update – Scroll bar real-time update (Old Version) Drag movement triggering scroll bar update – Scroll bar real-time update (New Version)  Next, we have canvas pan synchronization. In short, canvas pan updates the scroll bar. As a result, the scroll bar position and canvas pan are always in sync. Again focus on the scroll bar at the bottom to spot the difference.  The scroll bar is not updated – Pan Synchronization (Old Version) The scroll bar updates in sync with the canvas pan – Pan Synchronization (New Version)  Lastly, there is canvas size calculation. In brief, besides the existing elements, we also consider the visible area of the canvas. Due to this, there are no awkward jumps after dragging or scrolling.  Noticeable jumps – Canvas size calculation (Old Version) Smooth updates without jumps – Canvas size calculation (New Version)   CONCLUSION  In conclusion, high cohesion while maintaining usability was the key goal here. We hope this will help users have a better experience using our editors.  Make sure to check out our . You can stay up to date on our releases, new tools and have access to exceptional articles. Thanks for reading. See you next time.  The post appeared first on .  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Wagner Lemos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting started with Decision Models (DMN)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.mastertheboss.com/uncategorised/getting-started-with-decision-models-dmn/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=getting-started-with-decision-models-dmn</id>
        <link href="http://www.mastertheboss.com/uncategorised/getting-started-with-decision-models-dmn/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=getting-started-with-decision-models-dmn"/>
        <updated>2021-12-09T15:19:14.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[The Decision Model and Notation (DMN™) is a modelling language notation created by OMG for the specification of business decisions and business rules. In this tutorial we will have an overview of what is DMN and which are the key constructs of this language that you can use to model your Decisions that drive your ...  The post appeared first on .]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>F.Marchioni</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OptaPlanner documentation turns over a new leaf]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/optaplanner-documentation-turns-over-a-new-leaf.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/optaplanner-documentation-turns-over-a-new-leaf.html"/>
        <updated>2021-12-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[   For years, has been offering the documentation in two formats: single-page HTML and PDF. This now changes with the launch a new documentation website, built using .  What’s so exciting about the new documentation?  First and foremost, it loads instantly as opposed to the old single-page HTML documentation. For example, if I want to read about repeated planning, I open the single-page HTML docs and wait nearly half a minute for the page to load, despite having a very good cable connection. With the new documentation, it took me only 2 seconds as each chapter has its own HTML page and thus the content that has to be loaded is limited.  This also means it’s now easier to effectively share links to a particular section.  Second, now you can search through the entire docs:    The search box at the top of the page shows suggestions as soon as you start typing. Each suggestion consists of the chapter and a link to where the search term occurs.  Third, if you spot a discrepancy in the documentation and would like to improve it, contributing was never easier:    Finally, this new documentation website is much friendlier to search engines, which should make it show up in Google search results more often than before.   BUILDING THE DOCUMENTATION WEBSITE  The documentation sources remain in the , but the website assembly, named optaplanner-website-docs, became a part of the :    Similarly to the entire optaplanner-website, the optaplanner-website-docs is built using Maven. The Maven module acts as a wrapper over Antora, which generates the static site from AsciiDoc sources.  There are two Antora playbooks referring to documentation sources. The first one, used by default, is antora-playbook.yml that refers to the latest OptaPlanner release.  ... content:   edit_url: '{web_url}/edit/main/{path}'   sources:     - url: git@github.com:kiegroup/optaplanner.git       # Updates with every release to point to the latest release branch.       branches: [8.12.x]       start_path: optaplanner-docs/src ...  To render the latest documentation:   1. cd optaplanner-website/optaplanner-website-docs  2. mvn clean package  3. Open the index.html located in target/website/docs in your browser.  The second Antora playbook, antora-playbook-author.yml, is activated by the author maven profile and refers to the current optaplanner local Git repository HEAD.  ... content:   edit_url: '{web_url}/edit/main/{path}'   sources:     # Assuming the optaplanner local repository resides next to the optaplanner-website.     - url: ../../optaplanner       branches: [HEAD]       start_path: optaplanner-docs/src ...  To preview local changes in the documentation:   1. Make sure the optaplanner and optaplanner-website Git repositories are     located in the same directory or change the local URL accordingly.  2. cd optaplanner-website/optaplanner-website-docs  3. mvn clean package -Pauthor  4. Open the index.html located in target/website/docs in your browser.   SUPPORTED DOCUMENTATION FORMATS  Introducing new formats does not have to result in abandoning the old ones, and in our case it does not. While I encourage everyone to visit the new documentation website, the existing formats continue to be published with every release as before.  Also, should you need to have a look at a particular version of the documentation, it’s still at your hand in the .   CONCLUSION  Since the 8.12.0.Final release, there is a new documentation website available under . The documentation is now structured into pages by chapters and searchable. The single-page HTML and PDF documentation remains available for every release.  ")  The post appeared first on .  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>rsynek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Configuring Podman for Quarkus Dev Services and Testcontainers on Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-devservices-testcontainers-podman/</id>
        <link href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-devservices-testcontainers-podman/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[Podman is a daemonless container engine for developing, managing, and running Containers on Linux systems. Since the release of version 3, Podman allows the user to run a service emulating a Docker API provided on a Unix socket. This makes it possible for Testcontainers and Quarkus Dev Services to be...]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Michal Jurč</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quarkus Tools for IntelliJ 1.9.0 released!]]></title>
        <id>https://quarkus.io/blog/intellij-quarkus-tools-1.9.0/</id>
        <link href="https://quarkus.io/blog/intellij-quarkus-tools-1.9.0/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[We are very pleased to announce the 1.9.0 release of Quarkus Tools for IntelliJ. This release adds support for Quarkus streams in the new project/module Quarkus wizard and fixes compatibilities with just released IntelliJ 2021.3. Quarkus streams When a new Quarkus project/module is to be generated, it is now possible...]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jeff Maury</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RESTEasy Releases]]></title>
        <id>https://resteasy.github.io/2021/12/02/resteasy-releases/</id>
        <link href="https://resteasy.github.io/2021/12/02/resteasy-releases/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-02T18:11:11.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automating Quarkus with GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://quarkus.io/blog/logicdrop-automating-quarkus-with-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://quarkus.io/blog/logicdrop-automating-quarkus-with-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[Logicdrop provides a business automation and data intelligence platform that enables enterprises to design their own solutions and run them in the cloud. We process millions of transactions a month across a global client-base and add significant value to mission-critical processes. The Challenge Since moving to Quarkus, our productivity quickly...]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>KimJohn Quinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Order picking optimization in warehouses and supermarkets with OptaPlanner]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/order-picking-optimization-in-warehouses-and-supermarkets-with-optaplanner.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/order-picking-optimization-in-warehouses-and-supermarkets-with-optaplanner.html"/>
        <updated>2021-12-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[   During the pandemic year, we saw many stores and supermarkets adapt their business in several ways. Sometimes these changes occurred from day to day. For example, as a consequence of the sharp decrease in customer physical visits, online orders increased exponentially.  How many of them were prepared to deal optimally with this increase… ?  In this blog post, we present the new OptaPlanner that shows how to complete online orders in an optimized way!   THE ORDER PICKING PROBLEM  The order picking problem consists of a set of orders that need to be prepared for delivery to various customers. Each order is composed of a set of order items (the requested products). These products are located on shelves in the warehouse or in the supermarket and occupy a specific volume of space.  To complete the orders, there is a set of available trolleys that follow a calculated path in the supermarket and pick the order items. One order item is picked on each step of this path. The location of the products within the warehouse determine the path of the trolley, and the space in each trolley is divided into a number of buckets with a specified capacity.  The goal of the order picking problem is to calculate a picking plan that provides the path for each trolley and considers the following constraints:   * The distance to travel by the trolleys is minimized.  * All the order items must be picked.  * Items from different orders mustn’t be mixed in the same bucket, so enough    buckets must be reserved for each of the orders that will be prepared on the    same trolley.  * The bucket’s capacity is not exceeded by the total volume of the items on it.  * The splitting of an order into different trolleys should be minimized.  The following image shows a simplified view of the order picking problem input data and calculated picking plan:     WAREHOUSE STRUCTURE  To formulate the problem, the warehouse is defined as a set of shelves organized into columns and rows. Products are located on the left or right side of a specific shelf, on a specific row. The shelf, side, and row determine the product location.     THE NEW QUICKSTART   PROJECT STRUCTURE  The following image shows the maven project that comprises the quickstart:    The server side code is in the src/main/java directory and is organized in four packages:  bootstrap Helper classes for generating the randomized (but reproducible) data set used by the quickstart on application startup. domain Contains the domain model for representing the problem, and the planning classes used by OptaPlanner, for example the @PlanningSolution and the @PlanningEntity. solver Contains the ConstraintProvider implementation. rest Contains the REST API used by the client-side code to start and stop solving, and to retrieve the best solution to display.  The client code is in the src/main/resources/META-INF/resources/ directory. This directory has an index.html file that contains the basic HTML structure and loads the app.js file that calls the server’s REST API and makes the web page dynamic.   PLANNING DOMAIN MODEL     ORDER PICKING CONSTRAINTS  The order picking constraints are implemented using the Constraint Streams API, and they can be found in the org.acme.orderpicking.solver.OrderPickingConstraintProvider class.  The following constraints are provided:  requiredNumberOfBuckets Hard constraint to enforce the requirement that a trolley has a sufficient number of buckets for holding all of the elements picked along the path for each order, while at the same time the bucket’s capacity is not exceeded, and items from different orders are not mixed in the same bucket. minimizeDistanceFromPreviousTrolleyStep Soft constraint to enforce the requirement that the distance between the current trolley step, and the previous step in the calculated path is minimized. minimizeDistanceFromLastTrolleyStepToPathOrigin Soft constraint to enforce the requirement that the distance between the first trolley stop (the path origin), and the last trolley stop in the calculated path is minimized.  The conjunction of the minimizeDistanceFromPreviousTrolleyStep constraint applied to every step on the path, and the minimizeDistanceFromLastTrolleyStepToPathOrigin constraint, enforces the entire path minimization.  minimizeOrderSplitByTrolley Soft constraint to minimize the orders splitting into different trolleys.   EXECUTION EXPLAINED  When you first start the order picker, you will see that no picking plan or paths are calculated. No worries, it’s perfectly fine because the solver isn’t executed yet.  Let’s take a moment to take a look at the initial data set before starting the solver. You use the Unassigned tab to do this.   UNASSIGNED ENTITIES  The information about the unassigned trolleys and orders is shown on the different sub-tabs.  Before starting the solver, you can view all of the elements in the initial data set on this tab. However, as soon the solver starts solving, you will see that elements start disappearing from this tab. Good news, they’re becoming part of the picking plan!.  Unassigned trolleys    Unassigned Order_1     SOLVER EXECUTION  Click the Start button to start the solver. When the solver is started, you’ll see that the Picking plan tab will start showing the information about the calculated plan.   Note While the solver is running, the calculated plan is refreshed every 2 seconds, causing a screen refresh effect. You can use the stop solving button to mitigate this effect.   TROLLEY NAVIGATION  Use the Map tab to view a representation of how the different trolleys navigate the warehouse according to the calculated paths.    The post appeared first on .  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>wmedvede</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 2 December 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-12-02.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-12-02.html"/>
        <updated>2021-12-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, java, camel, debezium, openshift">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 2 December 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to our first December JBoss Editorial featuring the most interesting news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Here are the releases from the JBoss Community for this edition:</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-5-0-final-released/">Quarkus 2.5.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://camel.apache.org/releases/#camel-quarkus">Camel Quarkus 2.5.0</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_normalize_web_services_with_camel_k_and_atlasmap">Normalize web services with Camel K and AtlasMap</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/11/26/normalize-web-services-camel-k-and-atlasmap-part-2">Normalize web services with Camel K and AtlasMap, Part 2</a>, by Bruno Meseguer</p>
<p>Bruno’s article is a walkthrough Camel K 's implementation step by step. It also covers how to simplify data mapping with AtlasMap, which is a data mapping solution with an interactive web-based user interface.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_saga_pattern_with_processes_and_kogito_part_1">Saga pattern with processes and Kogito – Part 1</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/11/saga-pattern-with-processes-and-kogito-part-1.html">Saga pattern with processes and Kogito – Part 1</a>, by Tiago Dolphine</p>
<p>Saga is meant to provide transaction management using a sequence of steps that could be also called local transactions. In this article Tiago shows how to apply this pattern to Kogito processes.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_2_5_0_final_released_graalvmmandrel_21_3_and_usability_improvements_all_over_the_place">Quarkus 2.5.0.Final released - GraalVM/Mandrel 21.3 and usability improvements all over the place.</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-5-0-final-released/">Quarkus 2.5.0.Final released</a>, by Guillaume Smet</p>
<p>Announce the availability of Quarkus 2.5.0.Final which comes with the following main improvements:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Upgrade to GraalVM/Mandrel 21.3</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Support for JPA entity listeners for Hibernate ORM in native mode</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ability to add HTTP headers to responses</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Various usability improvements in extensions and our dev mode/testing infrastructure</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_smallrye_stork_meets_quarkus">SmallRye Stork meets Quarkus</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/smallrye-stork-intro/">SmallRye Stork meets Quarkus</a>, by Michał Szynkiewicz</p>
<p>Michał introduces SmallRye Stork and its Quarkus integration. Stork provides a way to locate and select services. It’s simple and customizable. Stay tuned as more articles will follow up on this topic.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_news_from_java_18">News from Java 18</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="http://www.mastertheboss.com/java/upcoming-news-from-java-18">News from Java 18</a>, by Francesco Marchioni</p>
<p>Java 17 was just released in September 2021 however the Java Community Process is already working on the next release of Java with a list of cool new features. This article discusses the top picks from the JEP Process.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_free_ebooks">Free eBooks</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Are you looking for a quick guide to migrating and modernizing your Java-based applications? Modernizing Enterprise Java walks you through the journey. Grab the eBook from  Natale Vinto and Markus Eisele:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/11/30/modernizing-enterprise-java-cloud-native-guide-developers#">Modernizing Enterprise Java: A cloud native guide for developers </a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another round of our JBoss editorial!</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/francesco-marchioni.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Francesco Marchioni</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Francesco Marchioni</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/francesco-marchioni</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="debezium" term="debezium"/>
        <category label="openshift" term="openshift"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Website refresh and GitHub Discussions]]></title>
        <id>https://quarkus.io/blog/website-and-discussions/</id>
        <link href="https://quarkus.io/blog/website-and-discussions/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[Quarkus website got a refresh and we enabled GitHub discussions for community conversations. Website refresh We’ve refreshed the look’n’feel with more contrast on pages for better readability. Cleaned up navigation menu and made a no fuzz "Getting Started" section to show the absolute simplest set of steps to get started...]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Max Rydahl Andersen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WildFly 26 Beta1 is released!]]></title>
        <id>https://wildfly.org//news/2021/12/02/WildFly26-Beta-Released/</id>
        <link href="https://wildfly.org//news/2021/12/02/WildFly26-Beta-Released/"/>
        <updated>2021-12-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[I’m pleased to announce that the new WildFly and WildFly Preview 26.0.0.Beta1 releases are available for download at .  For more information about the changes included in this release please consult the release notes, in the meantime the developers are working hard on tasks needed to prepare the base to add support for Jakarta EE 10 as the specifications become available.   RELEASE NOTES  The release notes for the release are , with issues fixed in the underlying WildFly Core betas listed .  Please try it out and give us your feedback, while we get to work on WildFly 26 Final!  Best regards,  Darran]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Darran Lofthouse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing the Filter EIP using Camel-k and Kogito]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/implementing-the-filter-eip-using-camel-k-and-kogito.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/12/implementing-the-filter-eip-using-camel-k-and-kogito.html"/>
        <updated>2021-12-01T22:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Camel is an Open Source integration framework that supports the implementation of the Enterprise Integration patterns (EIP). The Message Filter EIP allows you to eliminate undesired messages from a channel based on a set of criteria. The pattern uses a predicate to decide if the messages should be dropped or not.   Oftentimes the predicate logic can be complex, and might need more transparency and control by the business user. For instance, let us say we have transactions coming in, and we are only interested in the high risk transactions. As you can imagine, the rules that govern the risk can be complicated. This is where a rules engine can come in handy, to provide for a business user friendly methodology to define the predicate logic.   In this article we will discuss how to implement the Filter EIP using the cloud native technologies – Kogito and Camel-K. Kogito is designed to deliver powerful capabilities for building process and rules based applications natively in the cloud on a modern container platform. Camel K is a lightweight integration framework built from Apache Camel to run natively on Kubernetes  DEFINING THE TRANSACTION RISK RULES  Let us first define the transaction risk rules. As you can see below, the transaction risk is based on transactionAmount, transactionCountry and merchant information.  DEPLOYING THE DECISION SERVICE  The kogito project for this decision can be found . Let us now deploy this DMN as a kogito decision service on openshift. For this install the kogito operator.  Now let us create a kogito build using the repo above.  After the Build and Deploy the kogito decision service exposes a route so that we can invoke the decision service.  We can now invoke the decision service and test it.  DEFINING THE CAMEL ROUTE  Let us now define the camel route. We first invoke the decision service. The service returns back a payload with a boolean value indicating the risk. We then use this decision result in the predicate for deciding if this transaction needs further processing.  As you can see, the complexity of deciding if the transaction is high risk is offloaded to the kogito decision layer. The entire camel route definition can be found .  DEPLOYING THE CAMEL ROUTE USING CAMEL-K  We will now install the Camel K operator and deploy the integration micro service.  kamel install Kamel run FilterEIP.java  TESTING THE INTEGRATION MICROSERVICE  Now we can lookup the route that is auto generated by the REST DSL component and send in a transaction payload.  We can now see that the data is now available in the kafka topic.  Notice the header information, where we set the decision evaluation to decide if the transaction needs to be sent to kafka.  We will now send in a request, with a low risk.  Now, we can see the risk is evaluated to be false and this transaction is filtered for post processing, so we don’t see it on the kafka topic.  Similarly, it is possible to plug in decision points to other EIP patterns like content routing. Check out this from Matteo Mortari about how you can use DMN decisions for content based routing in Camel.  References    The post appeared first on .  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Sadhana Nandakumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 18 November 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-11-18.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-11-18.html"/>
        <updated>2021-11-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, kogito, java, resteasy, camel, reactive">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 18 November 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Here are the releases from the JBoss Community for this edition:</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-4-2-final-released/">Quarkus 2.4.2</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/11/kogito-1-13-0-released.html">Kogito 1.13.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://camel.apache.org/blog/2021/11/RELEASE-3.13.0/">Camel 3.13.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://camel.apache.org/blog/2021/11/camel-quarkus-release-2.4.0/">Camel Quarkus 2.4.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/apache/camel-k/releases/tag/v1.7.0/">Camel K 1.7.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://in.relation.to/2021/11/09/hibernate-reactive-1_1_0_Final/">Hibernate Reactive 1.1.0.Final</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://resteasy.github.io/2021/11/04/resteasy-5.0.0-release/">RESTEasy 5.0.0</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_test_driven_development_with_quarkus">Test-driven development with Quarkus</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/11/08/test-driven-development-quarkus">Test-driven development with Quarkus</a>, by Eric Deandrea</p>
<p>Eric’s article provides a detailed walkthrough of how to take advantage of Quarkus continuous testing and Dev UI for test-driven development. Eric also provides a sample repository that you can use to follow along with the article.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_boost_throughput_with_resteasy_reactive_in_quarkus_2">Boost throughput with RESTEasy Reactive in Quarkus 2.</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/11/04/boost-throughput-resteasy-reactive-quarkus-22/">Boost throughput with RESTEasy Reactive in Quarkus 2.</a>, by Daniel Oh</p>
<p>Daniel shows how some simple changes in your REST endpoints can boost the throughput of your application using RESTEasy Reactive. He also shows how to use the Endpoint score dashboard to assess the performance of your endpoints.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_low_code_camel">Low Code Camel</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://www.nicolaferraro.me/2021/11/03/low-code-camel/]">Low Code Camel - How Kamelets enable a low code integration experience.</a>, by Nicola Ferraro</p>
<p>This excellent post shows how Kamelets is driving a deeper transformation towards "low code" development with Camel. Nicola Ferraro shows that you can use Kamelets directly with yaml or take advantage of the Karavan tool to design and visualize your integration flows graphically.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_getting_started_with_hibernate_reactive_on_quarkus">Getting started with Hibernate reactive on Quarkus</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="http://www.mastertheboss.com/soa-cloud/quarkus/getting-started-with-hibernate-reactive/">Getting started with Hibernate reactive on Quarkus</a>, by F. Marchioni</p>
<p>Reactive everywhere! In this post, F. Marchioni helps us get started with Hibernate reactive, providing a step-by-step from project creation to configuration and coding.</p>
<p>The post covers the "classic" Hibernate ORM, but Hibernate Reactive can also be applied to Panache.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_java_lts_perspective_of_a_library_author">Java LTS - perspective of a library author</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://emmanuelbernard.com/blog/2021/11/15/java-lts/">Java LTS - perspective of a library author</a>, by Emmanuel Bernard</p>
<p>Oracle is proposing a change to the Java LTS lifecycle from the current 3 years for 2 years. In this post, Emmanuel Bernard put some light on the challenges, from the perspective of a library author, that such changes may bring to the complex Java ecosystem.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_videos">Videos</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>YouTube is such a great platform to share knowledge, here are my top picks for this week’s editorial:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/stH_jA5f5eM">First Look at Testcontainers Cloud and Quarkus</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/VGAnVX1lCxg">Quarkus Insights #69: Performance and costs of reactive libraries in Java</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/C5NGczQMHu0">KIELive #51 TrustyAI: Ensuring the Fairness and Transparency of Decision Models</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another round of our JBoss editorial!</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/alex-porcelli.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Alex Porcelli</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Porcelli</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/alex-porcelli</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="resteasy" term="resteasy"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="reactive" term="reactive"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 04 November 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-11-04.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-11-04.html"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, kogito, infinispan, vert.x, java, wildfly, elytron, jbang">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 04 November 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Congrats on all the releases and great work from the community!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/10/27/infinispan-operator-2-2-final">Infinispan Operator 2.2.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/11/04/WildFly2501-Released/">WildFly 25.0.1</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-2-1/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.2.1</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-2-0/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.2.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-4-1-final-released/">Quarkus 2.4.1</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-4-0-final-released/">Quarkus 2.4.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/intellij-quarkus-tools-1.8.0/">Quarkus Tools for IntelliJ 1.8.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-3-1-final-released/">Quarkus 2.3.1</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_keycloak_x">Keycloak.X</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org/2021/10/keycloak-x-update">Keycloak.X Update</a>, by Stian Thorgersen</p>
<p>Stian’s informative article takes us through the highlights and goes into detail about what’s coming with Keycloak.X.
He also shares the roadmap for all the work that lies ahead for the Keycloak team.
It looks like some awesome changes are coming with Keycloak.X so get ready!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kogito_public_api_the_road_ahead">Kogito Public API: The Road Ahead</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/11/the-road-towards-a-kogito-public-api.html">The Road Towards a Kogito Public API</a>, by Edoardo Vacchi</p>
<p>Edoardo gives an overview of the principles and reasoning that he and the Kogito team have put into the design of their new public API.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wildfly_s2i_v2_architecture_overview">WildFly S2I v2 Architecture Overview</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/10/29/wildfly-s2i-v2-overview/">WildFly S2I v2 architecture overview</a>, by Jean-François Denise</p>
<p>This informative post describes a set of pain points that the WildFly team plan to address with a re-architecture of the S2I images.
JF Denise goes into detail and explains the benefits of the new approach that will offer more flexibility, increased efficiency , and a greatly improved user experience.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_distributed_security_realms_in_elytron">Distributed Security Realms in Elytron</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/distributed-realm/">Using distributed realm in Elytron</a>, by Diana Krepinska Vilkolakova</p>
<p>Diana treats us to an overview of distributed security realms in Elytron that combine identities located across multiple security realms of any type into a single security realm.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_securing_wildfly_applications_with_openid_connect">Securing WildFly Applications with OpenID Connect</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="http://www.mastertheboss.com/jbossas/jboss-security/secure-wildfly-applications-with-openid-connect/">Secure WildFly applications with OpenID Connect</a>, by F. Marchioni</p>
<p>This post covers a basic example for using OpenID Connect and the elytron-oidc-client in WildFly to secure applications.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_insights">Quarkus Insights</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Get your popcorn ready and sit back to watch some Quarkus insights.
Here are my top picks for this week’s editorial:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/VGAnVX1lCxg">Quarkus Insights #68: Hibernate Reactive 1.0 and Quarkus</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/oY8TtKrC_5I">Quarkus Insights #67: Testing Command Mode</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="vert.x" term="vert.x"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="elytron" term="elytron"/>
        <category label="jbang" term="jbang"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 21 October 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-10-21.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-10-21.html"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, vscode, java, vertx, wildfly">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 21 October 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome back to another edition of the JBoss Editorial, a bi-weekly editorial containing information about JBoss and Red Hat related news and software!</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Once again, let’s thank everyone who has contributed to rolling out new releases over the past two weeks!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/10/20/developer-workflows-using-vs-code-java-extension-10">vscode-java 1.0</a> - Bringing Java 17 support to VS Code!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/10/11/red-hat-software-collections-38-and-red-hat-developer-toolset-11-now-beta">Red Hat Software Collections 3.8</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vertx-4-2-CR1-released/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.2.0.CR1</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-3-1-final-released/">Quarkus 2.3.1.Final</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/10/12/WildFly-s2i-25-Released/">Wildfly 25 s2i images</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/10/12/bootable-jar-6.0.Final-Released/">Wildfly Bootable Jar 6.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/10/12/infinispan-13-final">Infinispan 13.0.0.Final</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wildfly">WildFly</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>This past week, the Wildfly Elytron team (a team specializing in server and client side security) participated in the <a href="https://ghc.anitab.org/programs-and-awards/open-source-day/">Open Source Day</a> hackathon.
It is an all day hackathon celebrating Open Source technologies and allowing participants to learn about Open Source and contribute to projects designed to solve real world problems.</p>
<p>Issues in the Elytron issue tracker were triaged ahead of the event and new contributors were onboarded and taught about Git, creating and submitting pull requests, and how Open Source works.
The event went well for the Elytron team with double the amount of PRs submitted than in the Summer Open Source Day!</p>
<p>We’d also like to mention that in Wildfly 25 support has been added for the MicroProfile Reactive Messaging 2.0. More information and a sample application can be found within <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/10/14/MicroProfile-Reactive-Messaging-2.0-in-WildFly-25/">the announcement</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_videos">Quarkus Videos</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The Quarkus team has been busy in front of the camera these last two weeks!
Six videos have come out, including a new Quarkus Insights.
These videos cover remote development, the DevCLI, DevUI, DevServices, and continuous testing.
Most of these are under five minutes, why not watch them all?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5FRcQ9lUhRo">Quarkus RemoteDevelopment</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1hTMyTiiNO4">QuarkusDevCLI</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XKsr6cX3qT4">Quarkus DevServices</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OQWalmv72Nc">Quarkus DevUI</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5LbYbZpsbIg">Quarkus Continuous Testing</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oY8TtKrC_5I">Quarkus Insights #67</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/jason-porter.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Jason Porter</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Porter</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/jason-porter</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="vscode" term="vscode"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="vertx" term="vertx"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 08 October 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-10-08.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-10-08.html"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, kogito, infinispan, vert.x, java, wildfly, elytron, jbang">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 08 October 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Congrats on all the releases and great work from the community!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-3-0-final-released/">Quarkus 2.3.0.Final</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-1-5/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.1.5</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/09/23/infinispan-13-cr1">Infinispan 13.0.0.CR1</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wildfly_25">WildFly 25</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/10/05/WildFly25-Final-Released/">WildFly 25 is released!</a>, by Brian Stansberry</p>
<p>It feels appropriate to call special attention to Brian’s release announcement of WildFly 15.
The entire team has done great work and Brian goes into detail about all the new features, including finishing the migration to Elytron-based security and Java SE 17 support.
Congrats to the WildFly community on another fantastic milestone!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_elytron_hacktoberfest">Elytron Hacktoberfest</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://wildfly-security.github.io/wildfly-elytron/blog/hacktoberfest-has-begun/">Hacktoberfest Has Begun</a>, by Farah Juma</p>
<p>Calling all hackers!!
WildFly Elytron is participating in this year’s Hacktoberfest.
Check out Farah’s post to register and contribute to Elytron, Elytron Web, or WildFly OpenSSL repositories.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_run_decision_manager_with_podman">Run Decision Manager with Podman</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/10/beginners-guide-to-rhdm-local-conainter-podman.html.html">Beginners Guide to Installing Decision Management Tooling in a Local Container using Podman</a>, by Eric Schabell</p>
<p>Eric’s step-by-step tutorial taught me how to quickly set up a running instance of Decision Manager in a local container.
I really enjoyed the tutorial and would recommend as a great way to introduce yourself to the world of process automation.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_authenticating_to_business_central_with_ssh_keys">Authenticating to Business Central with SSH keys</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/10/business-central-ssh-key-based-authentication.html">Business Central SSH Key-Based Authentication</a>, by Eder Ignatowicz</p>
<p>This brief article shows you how easy it is to configure authentication with Business Central using SSH keys.
At the end, Eder also combines JBang with JGit in a nifty way to use a different SSH keys and provides you with the code.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_insights">Quarkus Insights</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Get your popcorn ready and sit back to watch some Quarkus insights.
Here are my top picks for this week’s editorial:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/2cHX8HT7Z6A">Quarkus Insights #66: SNCF migration from WildFly to Quarkus</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/efPuzK2YM4I">Quarkus Insights #65: Boost Business Automation Productivity with Quarkus Dev UI</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="vert.x" term="vert.x"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="elytron" term="elytron"/>
        <category label="jbang" term="jbang"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 23 September 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-09-23.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-09-23.html"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, kogito, openjdk, ansible, java">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 23 September 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to yet another installment of the JBoss Editorial! September is coming to an end, but it has been a pretty busy month for the JBoss community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus">Quarkus</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Quarkus has really come a long way since the first release only a few years ago. A testament to the fact is certainly the compelling user stories released by the project’s team in the last weeks. First, we have <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/logicdrop-customer-story/">How Quarkus Improved Logicdrop’s Developer Experience and Process</a>, followed by <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/adoptium-customer-story/">Eclipse Adoptium Uses Quarkus for high volume Java SE distribution API</a>. And we even have a nice retail business use case, with <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/decathlon-user-story/">VCStream: a new messaging platform for DECATHLON’s Value Chain, built on Quarkus</a>!</p>
<p>So, if you have yet to jump onboard the Quarkus train, it’s really time to do so! And, to help you do it, you can check out this nice tutorial on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/09/20/quarkus-spring-developers-getting-started">Quarkus for Spring developers: Getting started</a>. Once you are hooked by Quarkus, go check out the <a href="https://quarkus.io/newsletter/12/">Quarkus Newsletter #12</a>!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kogito_never_stops">Kogito never stops!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Kogito and its ecosystem have been quite active lately. In the last two weeks, five different articles have been released, each covering very different aspects of the project:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/automatic-connections-with-line-splicing.html">Automatic connections with Line Splicing</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/an-object-model-marshaller-for-all-occasions.html">An object model marshaller for all occasions</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/manage-processes-and-tasks-using-kogito-consoles.html">Manage Processes and Tasks using Kogito consoles</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/new-dmn-boxed-expression-editor-what-is-new.html">New DMN Boxed Expression Editor – What’s new?</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/kogito-process-eventing-add-ons.html">Kogito Process Eventing Add-ons</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_openjdk_and_gc_pauses">OpenJDK and GC pauses</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>After all this Quarkus and Kogito action, if you are still looking for even more technical nitty, gritty details, you should certainly check out this article on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/09/16/shenandoah-openjdk-17-sub-millisecond-gc-pauses#thread_processing_in_java">Shenandoah in OpenJDK 17: Sub-millisecond GC pauses</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases_releases_releases">Releases, releases, releases…​</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As always, projects of the JBoss community have been quite active and released a few exciting new versions, including a beta of Wildlfy’s next major version!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/09/20/WildFly25-Beta-Released/">Wildfly 25 Beta released!</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-1-4/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.1.4 released!</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/kogito-1-11-0-released.html">Kogito 1.11.0 released!</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ansible collection for Apache Tomcat (JWS) and Wildfly (EAP)</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/ansible-middleware/jws-ansible-playbook">JWS Collection v0.0.2</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/ansible-middleware/ansible_collections_jcliff">Ansible Cliff Collection v0.0.10</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_decaf_ansible_for_jboss_middleware">Decaf' - Ansible for JBoss middleware</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In the past months, we’ve been doing some hard work to ensure that JBoss software can fit as neatly as possible within an Ansible playbook. There is a still a lot to be done, but we are already quite proud of to two Ansible collections we have released. The first one is called, JCliff, but will soon be renamed to WildFly, as it aims to integrate, as smoothly as possible, the app server into Ansible. The latest version (v.0.0.10) has already a few exciting features:
* systemd integration, a reusable role to help set up WildFly as a systemd service
* a reusable role to install JDBC driver and their module
* and, of course, more fine-tuning of WildFly’s subsystem thanks to the JCLiff (embedded in the collection) which allows Ansible to configure mod_cluster, sockets, JMS queues and so many other features.</p>
<p>We are also very happy about the release of JWS Collection for Ansible (v0.0.2), which allows us to quickly set up Apache Tomcat or its counterpart, JBoss Web Server, but also provides some nice features, like integration with systemd and common criteria (partial) compliance checking. Please check our blog entry about this <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/08/30/automate-red-hat-jboss-web-server-deployments-ansible">Ansible collection for Apache Tomcat / JWS</a> for more details!</p>
<p>(Given that those are projects I work on, I fully assume that this entry is a shameless plug :) )</p>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another installment of our JBoss editorial! Stay safe and healthy in the meantime.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="openjdk" term="openjdk"/>
        <category label="ansible" term="ansible"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 10 September 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-09-10.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-09-10.html"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, kogito, infinispan, vert.x, java, byteman">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 10 September 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Congrats to each team on completing all the hard work and thanks to all community contributors!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="http://bytemanblog.blogspot.com/2021/09/byteman-4017-has-been-released.html">Byteman 4.0.17</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-3-9-9/">Eclipse Vert.x 3.9.9</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-1-3/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.1.3</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/download/">Infinispan 13.0.0.Dev04</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-2-1-final-released/">Quarkus 2.2.1.Final - hardening release</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-2-2-final-released/">Quarkus 2.2.2.Final</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_lra_extension_and_microservice_reliability">Quarkus LRA extension and microservice reliability</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/using-lra/">An Extension for Long Running Activities</a>, by Michael Musgrove</p>
<p>Quarkus provides an <code>@LRA</code> annotations that lets you build more reliable service interactions.
Michael’s informative article breaks down the details and walks you through an example with microservices that coordinate long running actions that complete in an atomic manner.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_metadata_for_your_bpmn_nodes">Metadata for your BPMN nodes</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/leveraging-bpmn-capabilities-with-metadata.html">BPMN and Metadata – Leveraging app capabilities</a>, by Wagner Lemos</p>
<p>The BPMN Editor includes fields where you can add metadata to nodes, offering a versatile and flexible way to receive custom event notifications via process listeners.
Wagner’s article shows us how to control process flow with metadata, highlighting both its simplicity and usefulness.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kogito_in_action">Kogito in action</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/shopping-recommendations-in-pmml-kogito-at-work.html">Shopping recommendations in PMML – Kogito at Work</a>, by Gabriele Cardosi</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/09/bringing-drools-rules-into-the-cloud-with-kogito-a-step-by-step-path.html">Bringing Drools rules into the cloud with Kogito: a step by step path</a>, by Mario Fusco</p>
<p>The Kogito team do an amazing job providing hands-on, practical examples for real-world use cases.
Since our last editorial, Gabriele concludes a previous post by demonstrating how to set up a Kogito service that allows remote clients to get purchase recommendations to personalize a web shopping experience.</p>
<p>Mario Fusco’s latest entry on the Kogito blog gives a lot of food for thought and is highly recommended.
In his article, Mario digs into migrating from Drools and start using Kogito and Quarkus.
He shows you how to start building microservices that you can eventually deploy into Function as a Service (FaaS) environments to provide stateless rule evaluation.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="vert.x" term="vert.x"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="byteman" term="byteman"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 27 August 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-08-27.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-08-27.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, wildfly, keycloak, kogito, infinispan, vert.x, java, narayana">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 27 August 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_calling_all_kogito_dmn_contributors">Calling all Kogito DMN contributors</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Guilherme Carreiro brings us the second in a series of posts that guide you through contributing to Kogito’s DMN editor, <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/dmn-editor-contributors-guide-part-2.html">DMN editor – Contributors Guide – Part 2</a>.
The post gives a nice overview of the DMN and the BPMN editors then links to some additional resources that guide you through the tasks of creating and testing Reactive components.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_resteasy_reactive_in_quarkus_2_2">RESTEasy Reactive in Quarkus 2.2</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Clément gives a very insightful look at how Quarkus and RESTEasy Reactive make your life easier when implementing HTTP APIs.
He also explains different dispatching strategies in Quarkus 2.2, based on method signatures to intelligently decide whether methods should be called on the I/O thread or a worker thread at build time.</p>
<p>Go read the full details in Clément’s post, <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/resteasy-reactive-smart-dispatch/">RESTEasy Reactive - To block or not to block</a> and take a look at some of the code examples he provides.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_narayana_lra_annotation_checker">Narayana LRA annotation checker</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The Narayana team have provided a Maven plugin that checks LRA (Long Running Actions) annotations.
This plugin helps developers avoid errors and follow the rules of the LRA specification.
There’s also a sample Quarkus project in that shows you how to use it.</p>
<p>You can read Ondra Chaloupka’s article here: <a href="https://jbossts.blogspot.com/2021/08/lra-annotation-checker-maven-plugin.html">LRA annotation checker Maven plugin</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_devconf_us_2021_designing_your_best_architecture_diagrams_workshop">DevConf.US 2021 - Designing your best architecture diagrams workshop</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Over on Eric Schabell’s blog, he announces the <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/07/devconfus-2021-designing-your-best-architecture-diagrams-workshop.html">Designing your best architecture diagrams</a> workshop that he will deliver at this year’s DevConf.US on Thursday, September 2.
Eric’s workshop takes attendees through the process of using open-source tooling to design architecture diagrams like an expert.</p>
<p>Congrats to Eric on getting the workshop accepted.
I’m sure it will be an invaluable workshop for all those who face the challenges of communicating complex architectural designs to project teams.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_apache_camel_at_kubecon_eu">Apache Camel at Kubecon EU</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Nicola Ferraro presented Apache Camel at the Kubecon EU conference that took place on August 19th, 2020.</p>
<p>Nicola’s presentation focused on Camel K integration with Knative with a detailed explanation and a super cool demo.
Visit his blog to read details and watch the video at <a href="https://www.nicolaferraro.me/2020/09/08/serverless-integration-kubecon/">Serverless Integration on Kubernetes with Apache Camel K</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Let’s start things off this week with a look the latest releases.</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vertx-4-2-Beta1-released/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.2.0.Beta1</a>! Great to see the first beta is here!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-1-4-final-released/">Quarkus 2.1.4.Final</a> is out! Follow the link to find the 2.1 migration guide and complete list of changes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/kogito-1-10-0-released.html">Kogito 1.10.0</a> is released alongside <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/kogito-tooling-0-12-0-released.html">Kogito Tooling 0.12.0</a> and the <a href="https://github.com/kiegroup/kogito-operator/releases/tag/v1.10.0">Kogito Operator and CLI Version 1.10.0</a>. Congrats to the entire Kogito team on all the hard work!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org/2021/08/keycloak-1502-released">Keycloak 15.0.2</a> is here. Grab the download link and docs from the link.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="vert.x" term="vert.x"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="narayana" term="narayana"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 11 August 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-08-11.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-08-11.html"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="Quarkus, DMN, Drools, Quarkys, Hybrid-cloud, kie">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 11 August 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>After short pause for the summer holiday, welcome back to this new installment of the JBoss Editorial! As always, the JBoss community has been quite active and there is quite a lot to cover today, especially on hybrid cloud and Kogito. Let’s dive right in!</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_hybrid_cloud">Hybrid Cloud</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>During the last weeks, Christina Lei did a quite interesting series of articles on hybrid cloud. After an <a href="https://wei-meilin.blogspot.com/2021/08/overview-of-making-hybrid-multi-cloud.html">overview of making hybrid cloud</a>, she explores some in-depth topic like <a href="https://wei-meilin.blogspot.com/2021/08/hybrid-multi-cloud-dynamic-security.html">dynamic security</a> or <a href="https://wei-meilin.blogspot.com/2021/08/observability-in-hybrid-multi-cloud">observability</a>. To conclude this serie, another article covers <a href="http://wei-meilin.blogspot.com/2021/08/a-study-of-hosting-and-managing-on.html">hosting and managing on hybrid cloud</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kogito_this_and_kogito_that">Kogito this and Kogito that!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>With the new release of <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/kogito-1-9-1-released.html">Kogito 1.9.1</a>, it’s time to explore (maybe again) all the potential of this framework. And fortunately, there are a lot of in-depth articles released recently doing just that! Let’s start with one on <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/how-to-capture-business-decisions-using-dmn-introduction-to-some-basic-patterns-and-their-value.html">how to capture decisions using DMN</a> followed by a tutorial on how to implement <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/kogito-task-deadlines.html">task’s deadline</a> with Kogito.</p>
<p>Once you get the hang of it, you’ll want to learn how to manage your <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/four-steps-to-author-bpmn-and-dmn-assets-on-gitpod-io.html">BPMN and DMN assets on gitpod.io</a>. Or explore <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/event-driven-decisioning-with-amq-streams-and-kogito.html">event-driven decisinning with AMQ streams and Kogito</a>. If those articles have but open your appetite for the framework, you can carry on with a tutorial on <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/how-develop-better-widgets-with-showcase-appl.html">how to develop better widgets</a> or how to <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/add-data-from-kie-execution-server-for-authoring-dashboards.html">add data from KIE server for authoring dashboards</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_techbytes">Techbytes</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Want to learn more? Don’t worry, we have few more intriguing technical articles for you:</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/dynamic-db-pool-config-with-sql-client/">Dynamic DB pool configuration with SQL client</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/07/26/modernizing-applications-apache-camel-javascript-and-red-hat-openshift">Modernizing applications with Camel, JS and OpenShift</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases">Releases</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As always, the JBoss community has been releasing new version at a steady stream:</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-1-2-final-released/">Quarkus 2.1.2 Final</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/08/kogito-1-9-1-released.html">Kogito 1.9.1</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2021/08/keycloak-1501-released.html">Keycloak 15.0.1</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another installment of our JBoss editorial! Stay safe and healthy in the meantime.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Quarkus" term="Quarkus"/>
        <category label="DMN" term="DMN"/>
        <category label="Drools" term="Drools"/>
        <category label="Quarkys" term="Quarkys"/>
        <category label="Hybrid-cloud" term="Hybrid-cloud"/>
        <category label="kie" term="kie"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 14 July 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-07-14.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-07-14.html"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, DMN, Drools, Wildfly, transactions, narayana, kie">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 14 July 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to this edition of the JBoss Editorial bringing you news and updates from the community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_from_the_community">From the community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In <a href="https://jbossts.blogspot.com/2021/07/narayana-lra-update.html">this post</a> the Narayana team begins a new blog series on Long Running Actions, a compensation-based approach to transactions.</p>
<p>The KIE Tooling team <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/07/instantaneous-feedback-loop-for-dmn-authoring-with-dmn-runner.html">announce</a> the new DMN Runner on <a href="http://dmn.new">dmn/new</a>.</p>
<p>Gabriele Cardosi provides a concrete example of a recommendation engine based on top of PMML in <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/07/shopping-recommendations-in-pmml.html">Shopping recommendations in PMML</a>.</p>
<p>Luca Molteni teaches us <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/07/how-to-start-contributing-to-drools-executable-model.html">How to start contributing to Drools Executable Model</a></p>
<p>Eric Schabell continues his blog series on Cloud Adoption with a <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/06/cloud-adoption-example-adoption-architeccture.html">an Example adoption architecture</a>.</p>
<p>Read this post by Jeff Mesnil to learn how to <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/07/01/wildfly-preview-bootable-jar/">Run WildFly Preview of Jakarta EE 9.1 with Bootable Jar</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_developers_on_film">Developers on film</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>We don’t just publish blog posts! Here’s some recordings of live community events that happened over the past 2 weeks.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n6D6a4G6ozg">Quarkus Insights #56: Quarkus Configuration</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e_kwOJE2vQo&amp;">Quarkus Insights #57: Quarkus CLI</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BIZHbsDAhm4">KIE Live #38: Destroy wrong beliefs and run real processes</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u3KbGjEkkDM">KIE Live #39: Migrating Drools to the cloud with Kogito: a step by step path</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases">Releases</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-0-2-final-released/">Quarkus 2.0.2.Final</a> The second bug-fix release to the recent, huge <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-0-0-final-released/">Quarkus 2.0 release</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/07/kogito-tooling-0-11-0-released.html">Kogito Tooling 0.11.0</a> Several bug fixes and improvements, including the new DMN Runner on <a href="https://dmn.new/">dmn.new</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://resteasy.github.io/2021/07/08/resteasy-4.7.0.Final/">RESTEasy 4.7.0.Final</a>. Including a <a href="https://docs.jboss.org/resteasy/docs/4.7.0.Final/userguide/html/RESTEasy_Embedded_Container.html#d4e2922">Reactor-Netty server adaptor</a>, Better support for Java 16 and the up and coming Java 17 release and <a href="https://issues.redhat.com/browse/RESTEASY-2943">Support for reactive publishers</a> for the HTTP client.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.davsclaus.com/2021/07/apache-camel-311-whats-new.html">Apache Camel 3.11</a>. The next long term support release of Camel. See the blog post for what’s new since 3.10.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/paul-robinson.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Paul Robinson</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robinson</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/paul-robinson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="DMN" term="DMN"/>
        <category label="Drools" term="Drools"/>
        <category label="Wildfly" term="Wildfly"/>
        <category label="transactions" term="transactions"/>
        <category label="narayana" term="narayana"/>
        <category label="kie" term="kie"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 01 July 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-07-01.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-07-01.html"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, DMN, Drools, Wildfly, Infinispan, microservices">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 01 July 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Congrats to all the teams on their hard work!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/06/29/infinispan-js-client">Inifinispan Node.js Client 0.9.0</a> This was released last week and includes the ability for the Node.js client to connect with different SASL authentication mechanisms.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-1-1/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.1.1 released!</a> Mostly bug fixes, but there were a few small features implemented. Check the announcement for more details.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-0-0-final-released/">Quarkus 2.0.0.Final released - Vert.x 4, MicroProfile 4, Continuous Testing and much more</a>. Certainly a much anticipated release! Quarkus 2 has been in the works for months and the team is very excited for the release. A number of things have changed, so be sure to read the announcement and migration guide as you work on migrating those Quarkus apps!</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_from_the_community">From the community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Karina Varela has a post about <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/06/24/automating-rule-based-services-java-and-kogito">automating rule-based services with Java and Kogito</a> up on the Red Hat Developer Blog. The post focuses on Kogito and using it to build, package, and automate the deployment of those rule-based services on Kubernetes and OpenShift!</p>
<p>James Falkner quickly tackles <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/07/01/resteasy-reactive-and-more-quarkus-20">RESTEasy Reactive in Quarkus 2.0</a> over on the Red Hat Developer Blog. With the release of Quarkus 2.0 there are a number of things that have improved. Using REST in a reactive way is one of them. Quarkus 2.0 utilizes Eclipse Vert.x 4 and does some optimizations at build time to further increase performance of REST services.</p>
<p>If you’re using Red Hat 3scale API Management and have a need to use WebSockets, be sure to check out Srikanth Kalluru’s <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/07/01/how-expose-websocket-endpoint-using-red-hat-3scale-api-management">blog post</a> for a quick three step walk through of how to get it done!</p>
<p>Mauro Vocale has a three part series, part four is not out yet, about moving Java programs to the cloud. <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/06/25/making-java-programs-cloud-ready-part-1-incremental-approach-using-jakarta-ee">Part one</a> introduces you to the legacy application and gets it up and running on OpenShift. This gets you familiar with what the application does and what to expect from further refactorings in subsequent posts. In <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/06/28/making-java-programs-cloud-ready-part-2-upgrade-legacy-java-application-jakarta">part two</a> the application will move from Java 8 to Java 11, JBoss EAP 7.3 and Jakarta EE. Lastly, in <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/06/30/making-java-programs-cloud-ready-part-3-integrate-microprofile-services">part three</a> the application will be moved to microservices. Additional monitoring tools will be introduced including Prometheus and Jaeger. The application will be updated for handling restarts, health checks, and other configuration settings.</p>
<p>Over in the BPM arena, there are three posts to take a look at: <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/06/custom-logic-in-bpmn.html">Custom logic in BPMN</a> by Kirill Gaevksii, <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/07/how-to-start-contributing-to-drools-executable-model.html">How to start contributing to Drools executable model</a> where Luca Molteni discusses getting your feet with contributing to Drools’s "Executable Model Compiler". Lastly, Matteo Mortari discusses <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/06/intelligent-kafka-message-routing-using-drools-dmn-engine-and-apache-camel.html">using Drools DMN and Apache Camel to intelligently route Kafka messages</a>. It includes a video as well as various examples and code to really sink your teeth into.</p>
<p>Wildfly 24.0.0.Final includes a preview of Jakarta EE 9.1 features. Jeff Mesnil discusses <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/07/01/wildfly-preview-bootable-jar/">how to try these features out using a bootable jar</a>. There’s also a section about getting up and running using OpenShift!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_developers_on_film">Developers on film</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Get your popcorn ready and sit back to watch some videos from our community.
Here are my top picks for this week’s editorial:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JOv1K_wj6Vo">Quarkus Insights #54: Kotlin on Quarkus</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WyeaF2pk8Ec">Quarkus Insights #55: Quarkus 2.0 Launch</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HQHjrf3i91Q">KIE Live #36: How to play with DMN</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pj8or38w2eQ">KIE Live #37: How to work with dashboards layouts</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/jason-porter.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Jason Porter</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Porter</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/jason-porter</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="DMN" term="DMN"/>
        <category label="Drools" term="Drools"/>
        <category label="Wildfly" term="Wildfly"/>
        <category label="Infinispan" term="Infinispan"/>
        <category label="microservices" term="microservices"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 18 June 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-06-18.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-06-18.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, wildfly, keycloak, kogito, infinispan, vert.x, java, narayana">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 18 June 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Congrats to all the teams on their hard work!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org/2021/06/keycloak-1400-released">Keycloak 14.0.0</a> is released! This release adds Financial-grade API (FAPI) support and lots of improvements.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://bytemanblog.blogspot.com/2021/06/byteman-4016-has-been-released.html">Byteman 4.0.16</a> has shipped and is now the latest version if you’re running Java version 9 to 17.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/06/17/WildFly24-Final-Released/">WildFly 24</a> is here and brings lots of awesome work. There’s too much to sum up here so click the link and check out the release notes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-0-0-cr3-released/">Quarkus 2.0.0.CR3</a> is here. Towards 2.0 final!!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-13-7-final-released/">Quarkus 1.13.7.Final</a> is available as a maintenance release.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-1-0/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.1.0</a> is available with lots of exciting features. Go download and start using it!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-3-9-8/">Eclipse Vert.x 3.9.8</a> is also here with numerous bug fixes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://jbossts.blogspot.com/2021/06/narayana-5120final-released.html">Narayana 5.12.0.Final</a> has been shipped. This version gives several enhancements and fixes some bugs. Go grab it!</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_from_the_community">From the community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Katia and Ryan on the Infinispan team released a nice two-part series of posts that explained how they built an online game across data centers and multiple cloud providers for this year’s Summit keynote demonstration.
In the first part, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/05/28/building-real-time-leaderboard-red-hat-data-grid-and-quarkus-hybrid-kubernetes">Building a real-time leaderboard with Infinispan and Quarkus on a hybrid Kubernetes deployment</a>, Katia and Ryan describe how they designed and implemented various services using Infinispan and Quarkus.
With part two, they explain how using the Infinispan Operator greatly reduced the complexity of standing up their clusters, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/06/08/create-and-manage-red-hat-data-grid-services-hybrid-cloud">Creating and managing Infinispan services in the hybrid cloud</a>.</p>
<p>Tommaso Teofili’s recent post, <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/06/autotuning-lime-explanations-with-few-predictions.html">Autotuning LIME explanations with few predictions</a>, outlines how to automatically tune LIME hyperparameters to achieve more stable explanations and comes with a PR that lets you dig into all the technical aspects covered in the post.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/06/rhpam-connectivity-to-external-amq-configurations-in-openshift.html">RHPAM connectivity to external AMQ configurations in OpenShift</a> by Michael Perez takes an in-depth look at connecting to an external AMQ with the aim of lowering the memory footprint for RHPAM pods as well as other deployment optimizations.
It’s an interesting read with good technical considerations to sink your teeth into so go give it a look.</p>
<p>Over on the WildFly blog, Jeff Mesnil walks us through the process of changing logging levels for cloud-based WildFly applications on the fly.
Take a look at Jeff’s script and straightforward commands to help you easily modify logs for debugging in his post, <a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/06/15/change-log-level-wildfly-cloud/">How to Change Logging Level for WildFly on the Cloud</a>.</p>
<p>Bilgin Ibryam is back with a post on the Red Hat Developer blog titled <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/06/14/application-modernization-patterns-apache-kafka-debezium-and-kubernetes">Application modernization patterns with Apache Kafka, Debezium, and Kubernetes</a>.
I really enjoyed this one as Bilgin expertly puts application modernization in context and examines different patterns, tools, and open-source ecosystems that can help you migrate brown-field systems to more modern, event-driven services as well as design green-field services that are future proof by providing the ability to evolve over time.
Be sure to catch up on this one if you haven’t already read it.</p>
<p>Just in time for your summer reading list the first book dedicated to Keycloak has been published, <a href="https://www.keycloak.org/2021/06/book.adoc">Keycloak - Identity and Access Management for Modern Applications</a>.
Congrats to authors Stian Thorgersen and Pedro Igor Silva.
It’s an impressive achievement and no doubt the book is full of invaluable expertise.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_evangelists_corner">Evangelist’s corner</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In our last editorial we mentioned Eric Schabell’s series on a retail data framework.
Since then Eric has obviously been hard at work as his next two posts in the series, <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/05/retail-data-framework-common-architectural-elements.html">Retail data framework - Common architectural elements</a> and <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/06/retail-data-framework-example-data-architecture.html">Retail data framework - Example data architecture</a>.
If you haven’t caught up on that series yet, then I highly recommend taking a look to learn about data flows and management in a retail context.</p>
<p>Eric has also posted the first in his next series, <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/05/cloud-adoption-an-architectural-introduction.html">Cloud adoption - An architectural introduction</a>.
This series is focused on proven integrations, structures, and interactions with the goal of enabling readers to implement and adopt cloud-based solutions using open-source technologies.
I’m really excited about this series and can’t wait to see what Eric brings in his next posts.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_developers_on_film">Developers on film</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Get your popcorn ready and sit back to watch some videos from our community.
Here are my top picks for this week’s editorial:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/ETTMBWEBfLY">Quarkus Insights #51: Answering questions from the community</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/pYhaZYX0kq4">Quarkus Insights #53: Java Memory - why should you care</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/ngXii5sA_nA">Building Kubernetes Native Java with the Quarkus CLI</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="vert.x" term="vert.x"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="narayana" term="narayana"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 31 May 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-05-31.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-05-31.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, wildfly, keycloak, kogito, infinispan, camel, jgroups, vert.x">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 31 May 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_hello_again">Hello again</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>To our community and all our readers,</p>
<p>I’d like to start this edition with a sincere and frank apology on behalf of the editorial team for the posts we missed in the last month.</p>
<p>There’s been a lot of awesome content that our community has shared and multiple project releases packed with useful new features and clever enhancements.
We’re long overdue in highlighting and celebrating all the great work that JBoss teams are doing, not to mention all the brilliant work of our evangelists and other contributors.</p>
<p>It’s been a busy past few weeks and we’ve got a lot of great articles and releases to catch up on, so let’s go.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Let’s start things off with congrats to all the teams on their hard work!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2021/05/jgroups-517-released.html/">JGroups 5.1.7</a> is released. Congrats, Bela!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-13-6-final-released/">Quarkus 1.13.6.Final</a> has shipped, which is the latest in a recent series of updates to version 1.13.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-0-0-cr2-released/">Quarkus 2 CR2</a> is out!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-1-CR2-released/">Vert.x 4.1.0.CR2</a> is here, right on the heels of the beta and CR1 releases.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/05/07/infinispan-12-1-2-final">Infinispan 12.1.2 Final</a> is available for download so go grab it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org/2021/05/keycloak-1301-released">Keycloak 13.0.1</a> is out!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/05/kogito-tooling-0-10-0-released.html">Kogito Tooling 0.10.0</a> has launched!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://bytemanblog.blogspot.com/2021/05/byteman-4015-has-been-released.html]">Byteman 4.0.15</a> is now available!</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_2_ama">Quarkus 2 AMA</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>With the recent release of Quarkus CR2, I’m sure we’re all anticipating Quarkus 2.0 GA.
As part of that release, Max and the rest of the Quarkus team are taking questions that they will answer on an episode of Quarkus Insights.
Use the <code>#quarkusinsights</code> tag to submit a question via social media and tune in to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ETTMBWEBfLY">Quarkus Insights #51: Q &amp; A - Part II</a> on June 2 to hear your questions answered.</p>
<p>Follow the social media links to post your question to the Quarkus team in their post, <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-insights-qanda2/">About to release Quarkus 2 - ask us anything!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_from_the_community">From the community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Jeff Mesnil has authored a very helpful and detailed look at building and deploying WildFly applications on OpenShift using Helm Charts in his post, <a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/05/05/helm-charts-for-wildfly/">Helm Chart for WildFly</a></p>
<p>Over on the Infinispan blog, Ryan Emerson has shared some details about the CLI compiled to a native image in <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/05/21/infinispan-cli-image">Infinispan Native CLI</a>, which is well worth a read.
You should also try downloading the latest Infinispan 12 server version and taking it for a spin with the native CLI!</p>
<p>Another recent one from the Infinispan team comes from Katia Aresti who, along with Ryan Emerson, explains how they <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/05/28/building-real-time-leaderboard-red-hat-data-grid-and-quarkus-hybrid-kubernetes">built a real-time leaderboard using Data Grid and several Quarkus extensions</a> to add some magic to this year’s Red Hat Summit Keynote.</p>
<p>Jacopo Rota on the Kogito blog explains how to <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/05/getting-started-with-trustyai-in-only-15-minutes.html">how to deploy a Kogito service together with the TrustyAI infrastructure on an OpenShift cluster in only 15 minutes</a>!</p>
<p>Have you been wanting to find out more about Shenandoah GC? Well, you should dive right in and check out Roman Kennke’s informative post, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/articles/2021/05/20/shenandoah-garbage-collection-openjdk-16-concurrent-reference-processing">Shenandoah garbage collection in OpenJDK 16: Concurrent reference processing</a>.</p>
<p>Bilgin Ibryam has recently posted <a href="http://www.ofbizian.com/2021/05/data-gateways-of-future.html">Data Gateways in the Cloud Native Era</a> that examines how data gateway components support different use cases and offer a solution for hybrid workloads spread across multiple cloud providers.</p>
<p>Last but certainly not least is Claus Ibsen’s webinar, <a href="http://www.davsclaus.com/2021/05/webinar-integrate-systems-in-age-of.html">Integrate systems in the age of Quarkus and Camel</a>, that explores how the trio of Camel Quarkus, Camel K, and Kamelets simplify the work to manage and bind systems together.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_evangelists_corner">Evangelist’s corner</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Eric Schabell never disappoints and his previous series on architectural elements in a real-time stock control solution for retail was no exception.
Eric rounds that series off nicely with <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/05/real-time-stock-control-example-stock-control-architecture.html">Real-time stock control - Example stock control architecture</a>.</p>
<p>Not one to rest for long, Eric Schabell launches a new series that tackles how to create a framework for accessing retail data from customers, stock, stores, and staff across multiple internal teams.
I’m sure it’s going to be a brilliant series so go have a look for yourself and find out more in his post, <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/05/retail-data-framework-architectural-introduction.html">Retail data framework - An architectural introduction</a>.</p>
<p>I also really enjoyed reading through Christina and Eric’s <a href="http://wei-meilin.blogspot.com/2021/05/tooling-guide-for-getting-started-with.html">Tooling guide for Getting Started with Apache Camel in 2021</a>.
It’s a well put together beginner’s guide to tools that can help with Camel applications.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_developers_on_film">Developers on film</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Get your popcorn ready and sit back to watch some videos from our community.
Here are my top picks for this week’s editorial:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/ILl85LLj93w">Quarkus Insights #49: Why I use Quarkus for Cloud Native Apps</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/7JPm1BFcrrk">What is Serverless with Java?</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/jBDmX85IjLM">No YAML! Kubernetes done the easy way</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/szza3DZlKzA">Quarkus DevServices</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="jgroups" term="jgroups"/>
        <category label="vert.x" term="vert.x"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 26 April 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-04-26.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-04-26.html"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, wildfly, keycloak, kogito, vertx, openshift">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 26 April 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another - slightly delayed, installment of our JBoss Editorial! If anything, the last two weeks in the Jboss community has been all about Quarkus and Kogito. Indeed, you’ll find in this post a trove of information and news on the two projects. But also, an exciting opportunity on Keycloak! Without any further ado, let’s jump right in.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_keycloak_wants_you">Keycloak wants you!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>If you are developers who is passionate about Keycloak, there is an opportunity of a lifetime for you! The <a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2021/04/jobs.adoc.html">keycloak team is indeed recruiting!</a>.</p>
<p>Also on the SSO project front, there is a cool post on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/04/23/integrate-red-hat-data-grid-and-red-hats-single-sign-on-technology-on-red-hat-openshift/">how to integrate Red Data Grid with RHSOO (Keycloak)</a>. Go check it out!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kogito_your_way_out_of_dodge">Kogito your way out of Dodge!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>First of all, a few days ago, yet another (see "Developers on film" below) <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/04/kogito-serverless-workflow-at-openshift-commons-briefing-2021.html">OpenShift commons briefing around Kogito</a> was delivered (19/04). If the video is (not yet) available, you can checkout the <a href="https://github.com/kiegroup/kogito-examples/">examples code from Github</a>.</p>
<p>Then, you may want to catchup on all <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/04/design-tools-highlights-on-kogito-and-business-central-april-2021.html">the cool features released</a> in the last weeks by the project.</p>
<p>If you are a user of VSCode, there are a few items for you. First, you can go and check out <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/04/the-score-card-editor-goes-online.html">the score card editors now online</a>. Second, there is a rather tutorial on <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/04/how-to-use-test-scenario-editor-to-test-your-dmn-asset-in-vscode.html">using the test scenario editor to validate your DMN assets in VSCode</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_evangelists_corner_off_with_their_head">Evangelist’s Corner: Off with their head!!!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>With the Red Hat Summit coming up tomorrow, you may want to check out this post of our very own Eric D. Schabell on the new format we are trying out this year: <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/04/red-hat-summit-2021-how-to-enjoy-this-three-part-event-series.html">Red Hat Summit: How to enjoy this three-part event series</a>.</p>
<p>On top of that, Eric has, as always, delivered a steady stream of content in the past weeks, with a focus on headless architecture. It started with a first post on <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/04/headless-ecommerce-an-architectural-introduction.html">Headless eCommerce - An architectural introduction</a>, to which he did a followup on: <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/04/headless-ecommerce-common-architectural-elements.html">Headless eCommerce - Common architectural elements</a>.</p>
<p>Headless architecture was also part of the <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/04/store-health-and-safety-architectural-introduction.html">Store health and safety architectural introduction</a>, which also was followed up by a post on <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/04/store-health-and-safety-common-architectural-elements.html">Store health and safety common architectural elements</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_tips_and_tricks">Quarkus tips and tricks</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As mentioned in our introduction, Quarkus has been the focused on many content released in the last weeks. On top of that, as you’ll see in the releases section of this editorial, the project has released not one, but two versions, including an alpha of the upcoming Quarkus 2.0.</p>
<p>Let’s first take a look at the content relating to Quarkus as a development platform. If you are still new to Quarkus, you may want to start then with this post about <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/04/07/deploy-quarkus-everywhere-with-red-hat-enterprise-linux-rhel/">deploying Quarkus everywhere with RHEL</a>. After that, still on the topic of packaging and deployment, you can learn how to <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/04/08/build-even-faster-quarkus-applications-with-fast-jar/">build even faster Quarkus applications with Fast jar</a>.</p>
<p>If you are already onboard Quarkus and his very neat development model, you’ll be quite happy to learn that <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/04/14/mandrel-a-specialized-distribution-of-graalvm-for-quarkus/">Mandrel, a specialized distribution of GraalVM for Quarkus</a> is coming up!</p>
<p>As you may be aware, Quarkus comes already with quite a few supported extensions, but you may still want to learn more about <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/solving-problems-with-custom-extensions/">custom extensions and which problems they can help you solve</a>.</p>
<p>If you are already running or developing a few webapps on Quarkus, you’ll be interested in <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/gui-react-patternfly/">learning how to add eye candy to it</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_developers_on_film">Developers on film</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>No time to read anything? What about relaxing and simply watching some nice technical videos instead?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/zx0_DIG6698">a brief overview of the Kogito implementation of the CNCF Serverless Workflow, named Serverless Workflows, at OpenShift Commons Briefing</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_release_release">Release, release, release…​</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As always, the JBoss community has been quite active and released a few major version in the last weeks:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/04/14/WildFly2301-Released/">WildFly 23.0.1 is released!</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Quarkus releases two different versions:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-13-2-final-released">Quarkus 1.13.2.Final was released</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-2-0-0-alpha1-released/">Quarkus 2.0.0.Alpha1 was also released</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-3-9-7/">Eclipse Vert.x 3.9.7 released!</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_decaf">Decaf'</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Enough Java? Too much jitters? Wants a palate cleanser? Here you with a cool two-part series on deploying the Mosquitto MQTT broker on OpenShift: <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/04/16/deploying-the-mosquitto-mqtt-message-broker-on-red-hat-openshift-part-1/">(part 1)</a> and <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/04/26/deploying-the-mosquitto-mqtt-message-broker-on-red-hat-openshift-part-2/">(part2)</a>.</p>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another installment of our JBoss editorial! Stay safe and healthy in the meantime.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="vertx" term="vertx"/>
        <category label="openshift" term="openshift"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 8 April 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-04-08.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-04-08.html"/>
        <updated>2021-04-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, wildfly, keycloak, kogito, elytron, containers, javascript">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 8 April 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Let’s start things off with congrats to the teams on their hard work!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/04/07/infinispan-12-1-0-final">Infinispan 12.1.0.Final</a> is released!<br>
This version of Infinispan, codenamed Taedonggang, includes a bunch of new features and fixes. Be sure to check out the announcement and start using it right away.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-13-0-final-released/">Quarkus 1.13</a> and <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-13-1-final-released/">Quarkus 1.13.1.Final</a> are now available with loads of great new features and improvements.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>Our very own Bela Ban has also recently finished off the work on <a href="https://github.com/belaban/JGroups/tree/jgroups-4.2.12.Final">JGroups 4.2.12</a> and <a href="https://github.com/belaban/JGroups/tree/jgroups-5.1.6.Final">JGroups 5.1.6</a>.
While there might not be an "official" annoucement on his blog, you can check Bela’s commit history for details.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_from_the_community">From the community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Let’s take a look at what’s been happening in the community since our last editorial.</p>
<p>First up is a post by Hao Wu, <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/04/how-to-interact-with-business-processes-using-camel-routes.html">How to Interact with Business Processes Using Camel Routes</a>, that neatly explains using Apache Camel to interact with business processes deployed in a KIE server.</p>
<p>Rebecca Searls, over at the RESTEasy blog, recently added a post titled <a href="https://resteasy.github.io/2021/04/05/blog-ParamConverter-with-Quarkus/">JAX-RS ParamConverter with Quarkus</a> that shows how to write RESTful services with Quarkus using the JAX-RS ParamConverter.</p>
<p>Eric Schabell has, yet again, delivered some great posts recently that demonstrate how community technology can solve real world business problems.</p>
<p>Finishing off a series of articles on point of sale architectures, Eric delves in a specific example in his post, <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/03/point-of-sale-example-image-distribution-architecture.html">Point of sale - Example image distribution architecture</a>.
Be sure to check the links at the end of the post in case you missed any of the other articles in his architecture blueprint for point of sale imaging in retail.</p>
<p>Not one to rest, Eric kicks things off with another series to share an architectural blueprint for the use case of deploying a container-based eCommerce website while moving away from tightly coupled existing eCommerce platform.</p>
<p>This first article in this series is <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/04/headless-ecommerce-an-architectural-introduction.html">Headless eCommerce - An architectural introduction</a>, which gives you an outline for the use case.</p>
<p>Eric then continues the series with his post, <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/04/headless-ecommerce-common-architectural-elements.html">Headless eCommerce - Common architectural elements</a>.
In this article, Eric goes into detail on common generic elements that make up the architecture blueprint for the headless eCommerce use case.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for the rest of Eric’s series!
I’m sure there’s lots more great information on the way.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_red_hat_developer_network">Red Hat developer network</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>James Falkner talks us through what’s new with the beta release of JBoss EAP 7.4 beta, including an detailed look at security and management improvement.
What to find out what’s going on? Take a few minutes and read his post, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/03/30/security-and-management-improvements-in-red-hat-jboss-enterprise-application-platform-7-4-beta/">Security and management improvements in Red Hat JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 7.4 Beta</a>.</p>
<p>Pasquale Congiusti also breaks down Camel K’s Kamelets and shows how they simplify complex system integration in his post, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/04/02/design-event-driven-integrations-with-kamelets-and-camel-k/">Design event-driven integrations with Kamelets and Camel K</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_developers_on_film">Developers on film</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Get your popcorn ready and sit back to watch some videos from our community.
Here are my top picks for this week’s editorial:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/eW_1rj2EKYM">3 new Java tools to try in 2021</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/RZbLwBuKxuw">Quarkus Insights #43: Writing Quarkus Extensions</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/U_SqX5uMbds">Improving security with Istio | DevNation Tech Talk</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="elytron" term="elytron"/>
        <category label="containers" term="containers"/>
        <category label="javascript" term="javascript"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 25 March 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-03-25.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-03-25.html"/>
        <updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="news, weekly_update, weekly_editorial, wildfly, vertx, quarkus, kie, camel, kogito">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 25 March 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial where we search through the JBoss Community for interesting articles and updates</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_introducing_the_prolific_eric_schabell">Introducing the prolific Eric Schabell</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>If you are a regular reader of the JBoss Editorial  you will be very familiar with the work of Eric Schabell, arguably one of the most prolific writers within the JBoss Community.  This edition is no different and sees Eric product three more articles.</p>
<p>Eric’s first article is a continuation of his Supply Chain Integration Blueprint discussion.  In this article Eric <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/03/supply-chain-integration-example-store-integration-architecture.html">expands on the common architectural elements discussed previously and outlines an example Store integration architecture for Supply Chain integration</a>.</p>
<p>Eric’s second article walks us through <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/03/codeready-containers-howto-setup-openshift-47-on-local-machine.html">the necessary steps for installing and running the OpenShift Container Platform 4.7 on our local machines</a>.</p>
<p>Eric’s final article kicks off a new series of articles within which he will introduce a new architectural blueprint covering <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/03/point-of-sale-an-architectural-introduction.html">"Simplifying and modernizing central management of distributed point-of-sale devices with built in support for container based applications"</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_whats_new_in_kogito_land">What’s new in Kogito land?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The <a href="http://kie.org">Kogito team</a> have been busy over the last few weeks publishing a number of interesting blog posts covering different aspects of the Kogito ecosystem.</p>
<p>We begin our coverage with an article written by William <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/03/building-prometheus-dashboards-in-business-central.html">demonstrating how to integrate metrics from a Prometheus datasource into the Business Central</a>.  The article walks you through the process from the creation of the data set within Dashbuilder, building the dashboard, how to consider filtering requirements and how to test the dashboard.</p>
<p>The next article, written by Manaswini, follows on from William’s article and <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/03/time-series-component-for-dashbuilder.html">demonstrates how you can further extend your dashboard through the integration and visualisation of time series data</a>.</p>
<p>The final article, written by Ricardo, introduces us to Kogito’s support for the <a href="https://github.com/serverlessworkflow/specification/">CNCF Serverless Workflow</a> specification, <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/03/restful-services-orchestration-with-kogito-and-openapi.html">allowing Kogito to provide a serverless interface to a service which can also be used to orchestrate RESTful services described through the OpenAPI standard</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_clustering_wildfly_using_dns_ping">Clustering WildFly using DNS ping</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>When running within a kubernetes environment it is natural to consider the <a href="http://www.jgroups.org/manual5/index.html#_kube_ping">KUBE_PING protocol</a> for cluster discovery, a protocol relying on the ability to query the kubernetes API server.  If you want to remain agnostic of your environment, or if you do not have sufficient permissions to query the kubernetes API server, then an alternative approach to consider would be the <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/03/12/Bootable-jar-jkube-clustering-dns-ping-openshift/">DNS_PING protocol</a> as <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/03/12/Bootable-jar-jkube-clustering-dns-ping-openshift/">demonstrated by Yeray using a simple WildFly bootable JAR application</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_optimizing_camel_3_9_no_more_saw_tooth_jvm_garbage_collection">Optimizing Camel 3.9, no more saw tooth JVM garbage collection</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The upcoming Camel 3.9 release will include some additional, significant improvements in the performance of the internal routing engine leading to a dramatic reduction in object allocation during continuous use.  The Camel team focussed on the five major areas of the codebase they had identified during performance testing with the intention of reducing the allocation count as much as possible, they managed to go one better and achieved a sustained object allocation count of zero!  For more information take a look at <a href="http://www.davsclaus.com/2021/03/apache-camel-39-no-more-saw-tooth-jvm.html">Claus' blog describing the effort</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_monitoring_quarkus_applications_on_openshift">Monitoring Quarkus applications on OpenShift</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>If you are running a Quarkus application on OpenShift you will most likely have a need for integrating with the centralised prometheus instance within the cluster.  This integration is fairly straight forward and can be achieved after following only a few simple steps <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/micrometer-prometheus-openshift/">as ably demonstrated by Jose</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_new_releases">New Releases</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://www.wildfly.org/">WildFly team</a> have announced</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>the <a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/03/11/WildFly-MicroProfile-Reactive-specifications-feature-pack-2.0/">2.0.0.Final release of the MicroProfile Reactive Specifications Feature Pack for WildFly</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the <a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/03/19/bootable-jar-4.0.Final-Released/">4.0.0.Final release of the WildFly Bootable JAR Maven Plugin</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/03/18/WildFly-s2i-23-Released/">23.0 release of the WildFly S2I images</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>The <a href="http://kie.org/">Kogito team</a> have announced</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>the release of <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/03/kogito-tooling-0-8-5-released.html">Kogito Tooling 0.8.5</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the preliminary release of their <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/03/scorecard-editor.html">PMML (4.4) Scorecard Editor</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://vertx.io">Vert.x team</a> have announced the release of <a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-0-3/">Eclipse Vert.x 4.0.3</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>That’s all for this edition of the JBoss Editorial, please join us in a couple of weeks when we will bring you more news and articles from the JBoss Community Projects.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/kevin-conner.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Kevin Conner</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Conner</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/kevin-conner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
        <category label="weekly_update" term="weekly_update"/>
        <category label="weekly_editorial" term="weekly_editorial"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="vertx" term="vertx"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="kie" term="kie"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 11 March 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-03-11.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-03-11.html"/>
        <updated>2021-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, wildfly, keycloak, kogito, elytron, containers, javascript">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 11 March 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Let’s start things off with congrats to all the teams on their hard work!</p>
<div class="ulist square">
<ul class="square">
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-12-1-final-released/">Quarkus 1.12.1.Final</a> is out with bug fixes and documentation improvements.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-3-9-6">Eclipse Vert.x 3.9.6</a> is now available and delivers several bug fixes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org/2021/03/keycloak-1204-released">Keycloak 12.0.4</a> is also released. Go check out their blog for full details.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_from_the_community">From the community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>There’s been a lot of activity since the last editorial so let’s take a look.</p>
<p>First up is Ramon Gordillo’s rather interesting take on moving legacy technology on Kubernetes.
Ramon starts by pointing out that even software that is considered "legacy" and traditionally on-prem is often packed with new and useful features.
Add to that the fact that many containerized applications still rely on legacy systems - "not all apps are greenfield" - and he builds a solid case for doing something that might otherwise induce a few gasps.
Go see how Ramon tackles running IBM DB2 in containers, <a href="https://blog.ramon-gordillo.dev/2021/03/trying-db2-in-kubernetes-for-developers/">Trying DB2 in Kubernetes for developers</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/02/migrating-jbpm-images-secured-by-ldap-to-elytron.html">Migrating jBPM images secured by LDAP to Elytron</a> by Gonzalo Muñoz Fernández is one that I thoroughly enjoyed.
If you’re not familiar with Elytron it is, as Gonzalo explains, Wildfly’s security framework that puts security management and application access into a single subsystem.
In his post, Gonzalo clearly describes and then steps through how to migrate jBPM images from PicketBox, which is a security subsystem based on JAAS login modules, over to Elytron.</p>
<p>Also on the Kogito blog, Paul Brown and Emily Murphy take on the challenge of <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/03/optimizing-covid-19-vaccination-appointment-scheduling.html">Optimizing COVID-19 vaccination appointment scheduling</a>.
Their post details the approach for using OptaPlanner to handle planning constraints and automatically assign vaccination appointments.
Getting vaccinations rolled out globally is a massive logistical and planning challenge so it’s comforting to know our community is providing tooling to get us all back to "normal".</p>
<p>The Red Hat Developer blog has a couple of recent entries focused on JavaScript that are both good reads.</p>
<p>Michael Dawson introduces us to the <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/03/08/introduction-to-the-node-js-reference-architecture-part-1-overview/">Node.js reference architecture from Red Hat and IBM</a> and explains their reasons for creating it.
The goal is to help developers make good choices when navigating the vibrant and extensive JavaScript ecosystem by recommending packages based on shared experience across teams and projects.</p>
<p>Joel Lord takes us through <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/03/04/building-rootless-containers-for-javascript-front-ends/">Building rootless containers for JavaScript front ends</a> to demonstrate how you can avoid security vulnerabilities and potential disaster.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_evangelists_corner">Evangelist’s corner</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Our ever productive Eric Schabell has brought us some fantastic content that should really get you thinking about community technology can apply to solve real world business problems.</p>
<p>Similarly to James and Emily’s post on the Kogito blog, Eric shows how <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/03/business-optimisation-architecture-example-vaccine-scheduling-.html">retail pharmacies can optimize scheduling to provide customer vaccinations</a>.</p>
<p>Eric also provides a <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/03/supply-chain-integration-an-architectural-introduction.html">architectural blueprint for supply-chain integration</a> that comes with a treasure trove of resources and is well worth delving into.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_developers_on_film">Developers on film</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Get your popcorn ready and sit back to watch some videos from our community.
Here are my top picks for this week’s editorial:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/ogbMLeU1ogk">Make your Quarkus apps even faster with Fast Jar packaging</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/BQMMd-RbXcE">Quarkus Insights #40: Behind the curtains with Quarkus tooling and workflows</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/ALeGqUAJrUU">Data gateways: Legacy data for microservices</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="elytron" term="elytron"/>
        <category label="containers" term="containers"/>
        <category label="javascript" term="javascript"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 25 February 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-02-25.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-02-25.html"/>
        <updated>2021-02-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, wildfly, kogito, openshift, bpm, microprofile, resteasy, keycloak, infinispan">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 25 February 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another installment of our JBoss Editorial! Today, we’ll focus on Kogito and the upcoming major release of Wildfly. Enjoy!</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wildfly_23_beta_microprofile">Wildfly 23 Beta: Microprofile</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As the release of the next major version of Wildlfy is coming up soon, Brian Stanberry took the time to write up a brief article on the <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/02/24/WildFly23-Beta-Released/">progress with MicroProfile</a>. If you have interested in playing with <a href="https://github.com/eclipse/microprofile/releases/tag/4.0">MicroProfile Platform 4.0</a> or see tech preview support for <a href="https://github.com/eclipse/microprofile-reactive-messaging/releases/tag/1.0">MicroProfile Reactive Messaging 1.0</a>, go check out <a href="https://download.jboss.org/wildfly/23.0.0.Beta1/wildfly-23.0.0.Beta1.zip">Wildfly 23 Beta1</a> and let us know what you think!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kogito">Kogito</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>If you are already a Kogito user or if you are interested in exploring this software, there were a few articles released in the past two weeks that you might find interesting. The first one is on <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/02/kogito-notifications-api.html">Kogito Notification API</a> which is followed nicely by the second one on <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/02/event-driven-decisions-with-kogito.html">Event-driven decisions with Kogito</a></p>
<p>If you want something more practical, you’ll certainly enjoy the third article on <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/02/3-steps-to-author-bpmn-dmn-editors-on-github-codespaces.html">3 steps to author BPMN and DMN assets on GitHub Codespaces</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_fast_jar_as_default_multipart_support_for_resteasy_reactive">Quarkus: Fast jar as default, Multipart support for RESTEasy Reactive</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Following up the recent release of <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-11-3-final-released/">Quarkus 1.11.3.Final</a>, <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-12-0-final-released/">Quarkus 1.12 was just released</a> and includes some exciting new features. First, fast jar is now by default and the framework added multipart support for RESTEasy Reactive. Go check it out!</p>
<p>And if you have not yet looked into Quarkus, a new tutorial has been released: <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/02/11/enhancing-the-development-loop-with-quarkus-remote-development/">Enhancing the development loop with Quarkus remote development</a>, so it’s the perfect opportunity to explore the framework potential and test it over OpenShift.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_evangelists_corner">Evangelist’s Corner</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As always, our very own Eric Schabell has provided the community with quite a lot of content in the last two weeks. First, you have a nice <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/02/business-optimisation-an-introduction.html">introduction to Business optimization architecture</a>, which can be followed by this other piece on <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/02/business-optimisation-common-architectural-elements.html">Business optimization architecture - Common architectural elements</a>.</p>
<p>Of course, Eric has not forgotten the famous OpenShift and delivered a pretty nifty <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/03/refcard-getting-started-with-openshift.html">RefCard - Getting started with OpenShift</a> published for DZone. Go grab it!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases">Releases!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-12-0-final-released/">Quarkus 1.12 released</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://download.jboss.org/wildfly/23.0.0.Beta1/wildfly-23.0.0.Beta1.zip">Wildfly 23 Beta1 is now available</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://resteasy.github.io/2021/02/18/resteasy-3.15.0.Final/">RESTEasy 3.15.0.Final is now available</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://bytemanblog.blogspot.com/2021/02/byteman-4014-has-been-released.html">Byteman 4.0.14 has been released </a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2021/02/keycloak-1203-released.html">Keycloak 12.0.3 released</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/02/12/infinispan-12-0-1">Infinispan 12.0.1.Final "Lockdown"</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another installment of our JBoss editorial! Stay safe and healthy in the meantime.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="openshift" term="openshift"/>
        <category label="bpm" term="bpm"/>
        <category label="microprofile" term="microprofile"/>
        <category label="resteasy" term="resteasy"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 11 February 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-02-11.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-02-11.html"/>
        <updated>2021-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, wildfly, kogito, openshift, vertx">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 11 February 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Here we are again, it’s been two weeks and we’re into the second month of 2021!
How quickly times flies!
In this edition, expect to find release information, blog posts, and general updates from around the JBoss Community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases">Releases!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-11-2-final-released/">Quarkus 1.11.2.Final</a> is the second maintenance release for the Quarkus 1.11 branch. The notable bug fix with this version is updating to Hibernate ORM 5.4.27.SP1 which fixes a potential data loss issue. Please see the <a href="https://github.com/quarkusio/quarkus/releases/tag/1.11.2.Final">full changelog for more info</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-11-3-final-released/">Quarkus 1.11.3.Final</a> is a quick bug fix release that focused on a regression making it impossible to build native executables if your project was using both RESTEasy and OpenTracing. <a href="https://github.com/quarkusio/quarkus/releases/tag/1.11.3.Final">Please see the full changelog</a> for more information.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/02/11/WildFly2201-Released/">Wildfly 22.0.1</a> has been released, about a month after 22.0.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vertx.io/blog/eclipse-vert-x-4-0-2/">Vert.x 4.0.2 released</a> recently. The 4.0.1 release also happened, but contained potential memory leaks and the team decided not to announce it and proceed with another quick release to fix the issues. <a href="https://github.com/vert-x3/wiki/wiki/4.0.2-Release-Notes">Please view the release notes for more details</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/02/kogito-tooling-0-8-3-released.html">Kogito Tooling 0.8.3 released</a> a few days ago. With the release of 0.8.1, the Kogito team released their official version of the BPMN and DMN standalone editors. This release builds on that and continues to allow you to embed the editor within your application. It also allows you to open DMN 1.1 and 1.3 assets. The post also contains a list of bugs squashed</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>We would certainly like to thank all those who helped complete these releases!
Each team is grateful for the help from the community.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_highlights_from_the_blogosphere">Highlights from the blogosphere</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Eric Schabell published a migration guide for a traditional JBoss BPM application running either within a VM or on bare-metal to running inside containers using OpenShift Container Platform.
In <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/03/4-easy-steps-for-migrating-projects-to-openshift-container-platform.html">his post he breaks the migration down into four steps</a>.
I won’t detail them all here, but the steps are very easy and you should be able to get up and running quickly on your own laptop, even without having some of the tech installed previously!</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/02/improvements-of-project-authoring-in-business-central.html">Abhishek Kumar discussed project authoring improvements within Business Central recently on the KIE Blog</a>.
The features he discusses are:
. Opening projects directly with a URL
. Changing the default asset page size
. Security permissions for project screen tools and tabs</p>
<p>Each of these help users in the authoring process within Business Central through either ease of use or security!</p>
<p>Still on the KIE Blog, <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/01/how-to-use-a-pmml-file-in-dmn-editor-vscode.html">Yeser Amer demonstrates how to use PMML models in the DMN Editor</a>.
PMML support was released with version 0.7.0.
PMML is an XML file describing a predictive model often generated by data mining or AI algorithms.
The support for this format within the VSCode plugin was recently released and follows the same usage patterns as those found within Business Central, so it may very well be familiar to some.</p>
<p>A number of blogs about Quarkus sprang up over the past couple of weeks!</p>
<p>Firstly, Georgios Andrianakis discusses <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/resteasy-reactive-faq/">achieving massive performance without headaches</a> in a RESTEasy application on Quarkus using RESTEasy Reactive.
He talks about the different models, how to use them, the best way to get performance out of each model, and why this will likely becoming the default model within RESTEasy on Quarkus in the near future.</p>
<p>Clement Escoffier <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/getting-started-amqp/">helps us get started with AMQP in Quarkus</a> with an in-depth demo similar to using Kafka.
He walks you through the basics and gives you a running project which he steps through to show you all the basics.</p>
<p>Over on the Red Hat Developers Blog, Eric Deandrea shows us a very cool trick, or maybe the power of Quarkus’s Spring compatibility, about running a Spring Boot application on Quarkus without changing a single line of Java code!
It is definitely worth the read, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/02/09/spring-boot-on-quarkus-magic-or-madness/">head on over to check it out</a>!</p>
<p>If you missed the announcement about Quarkus remote development, be sure to read up about it by Daniel Oh <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/02/11/enhancing-the-development-loop-with-quarkus-remote-development/">on the Red Hat Developer Blog</a>.
Using a mutable-jar package, you can deploy onto OpenShift and continue to develop remotely without having to build a new container and push every time you want to see a change!
What an amazing way to build on the cloud and make sure everything works correctly without having slow downs!</p>
<p>Yeray Borges of the Wildfly team <a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/02/01/Bootable-jar-jkube-clustering-openshift/">demonstrates how to deploy a bootable Wildfly application jar which caches the HTTP session state</a>.
It’s a useful option allowing you to build and test locally and then push to OpenShift with minimal changes ensuring your application still works in the cloud.</p>
<p>Lastly, Mario Fusco and Edson Yanaga have a presentation from a recent DevNation Live about designing a Java API.
Check it out over on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/devnation/tech-talks/design-java-apis">the Red Hat Developer blog</a>.
Certainly worth the watch if you develop APIs in Java (which should be most of you).</p>
<p>Thanks for being with us for another edition of the JBoss Weekly Editorial.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/jason-porter.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Jason Porter</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Porter</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/jason-porter</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="openshift" term="openshift"/>
        <category label="vertx" term="vertx"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 28 January 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-01-28.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-01-28.html"/>
        <updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, infinispan, openshift, camel, kafka, wildfly, keycloak">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 28 January 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases">Releases!!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Infinispan 12 release, codenamed <code>Lockdown</code>, brings a ton of new features and improvements.
Indexing and querying capabilities have seen a number of improvements with the help of Hibernate Search integration.
ProtoStream marshalling is upgraded with a new <code>@ProtoAdapter</code> annotation that lets you easily integrate third-party classes.
It’s a pretty elegant solution to what could present itself as a real headache for developers.
Speaking of marshalling improvements, Infinispan 12 also makes your life easier by automatically generating and registering <code>SerializationContextInitializer</code> implementations to marshall user types.
Also notable is the SPI for cross-site replication merge conflicts, which continues on the brilliant work that team has done to provide a solution for ensuring data integrity.
There’s a lot going on in Infinispan 12 and probably too much to try and sum up here so why not head over and read all the details in the <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2021/01/25/infinispan-12-final">Infinispan 12.0.0.Final Announcement</a>.</p>
<p>Congratulations to the entire Infinispan team on all the hard work.</p>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-11-0-final-released/">Quarkus 1.11</a> is here!
This release brings you RESTEasy Reactive, which is a new JAX-RS implementation for writing RESTful services.
Quarkus 1.11 also introduces the Dev UI so you can quickly visualize all your loaded extensions, access docs, and more.
Of course there are other things in Quarkus 1.11 but RESTEasy Reactive and the Dev UI look to be quite promising indeed.</p>
<p>The Quarkus team keep things rolling with the release of <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/intellij-quarkus-tools-1.3.0/">Quarkus Tools for IntelliJ 1.3.0</a> that adds codestarts to the Quarkus project wizard.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2021/01/keycloak-1202-released.html">Keycloak 12.0.2</a> is now available too!
Head on over to their site and check it out.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wildfly_bootable_jars_on_openshift">WildFly Bootable JARs on OpenShift</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Emmanuel Hugonnet <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2021/01/24/odo-bootable-jar/">shows you how to use WildFly’s bootable JAR feature</a> and the <code>odo</code> CLI tool to easily build and deploy applications on OpenShift.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_getting_started_with_apache_kafka_in_quarkus">Getting Started with Apache Kafka in Quarkus</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Clement Escoffier details how to get you started with Apache Kafka in Quarkus applications in less than 10 steps using Reactive Messaging.
Clement provides a GitHub repository with the code too so take a look at his <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/getting-started-kafka/">Getting Started with Apache Kafka</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_easing_the_keycloak_integration_tests_in_kie_server_with_testcontainers">Easing the Keycloak integration tests in Kie Server with Testcontainers</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Over at the Kie blog, Gonzalo Muñoz Fernández demonstrates <a href="https://blog.kie.org/2021/01/keycloak-integration-tests-in-kie-server-with-testcontainers.html">using Testcontainers to quickly and easily create integration tests with Kie Server and Keycloak</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_resteasy_wadl_module_in_wildfly">RESTEasy WADL Module in WildFly</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Wei Nan gives a straightforward example of <a href="https://resteasy.github.io/2021/01/18/deploy-resteasy-wadl-to-wildfly/">deploying the RESTEasy WADL module</a> into WildFly.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_insights_hibernate_search_6">Quarkus Insights: Hibernate Search 6</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Have you subscribed to the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Quarkusio/videos">Quarkusio YouTube</a> channel yet?</p>
<p>If not, head over and take a look.
There are always interesting discussions and cool speakers.</p>
<p>One recent video that I really enjoyed, and is timed well with the release of Infinispan 12, is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hwxWx-ORVwM">Episode #32</a> where Yoann Rodière joins the lads and introduces us to <a href="https://hibernate.org/search/releases/6.0/#whats-new">Hibernate Search 6</a>.
Yoann goes through all the exciting new stuff in Hibernate Search and explains how the search API gives you accurate and flexible full-text search for applications to overcome the limitations that come from SQL queries.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_apache_camel_and_java_flight_recorder">Apache Camel and Java Flight Recorder</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Claus Ibsen’s recent <a href="http://www.davsclaus.com/2021/01/apache-camel-38-and-java-flight-recorder.html">Apache Camel 3.8 and Java Flight Recorder</a> post breaks down how you can capture work steps with Flight Recorder to diagnose Apache Camel and improve performance.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_red_hat_developer_highlights">Red Hat Developer Highlights</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In another Flight Recorder post, Andrew Azores gives us a great tutorial on using <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/01/25/introduction-to-containerjfr-jdk-flight-recorder-for-containers/">JDK Flight Recorder for containers</a> running on OpenShift.</p>
<p>Finally, there is a great DevNation Tech Talk by Sebastien Blanc and Edson Yanaga on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/devnation/tech-talks/kubectl-quarkus">Building kubectl plugins with Quarkus</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="openshift" term="openshift"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="kafka" term="kafka"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss: 14 January 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-01-14.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2021-01-14.html"/>
        <updated>2021-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="wildfly, camel, keycloak, teiid, springboot, tekton, kubernetes, codeready, quarkus, jgroups">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss: 14 January 2021</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to the first installment of our JBoss Editorial for 2021! And to start the year, we have a brand new major release of the core product of the JBoss community! Yes, Wildfly 22 is out!</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wildfly_22_and_camel_3_7">Wildfly 22 and Camel 3.7</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Yes! We have a brand new major version of Wildfly! <a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/01/13/WildFly22-Final-Released/">Wildfly 22 is out!</a>.</p>
<p>This release includes support for use of log4j2 in applications, new base health and metrics subsystems to provide server observability for users who don’t need the application instrumentation that comes with MicroProfile Health and Metrics, and a number of other features related to management, provisioning, messaging and security. Plus numerous bug fixes, enhancements and component upgrades.</p>
<p>On top of that, there is also an updated version of the new tech-preview WildFly Preview distribution. This will allow the community have a look at what Wildfly developers are doing for Jakarta EE 9 support, along with other changes in the server architecture that are expected to appear later in 2021.</p>
<p>Wildfly 22 is already a nice treat, but we also have <a href="https://camel.apache.org/blog/2020/12/Camel37-Whatsnew/">Camel 3.7</a>, which also quite exciting, and fortunately for all of us, Claus Ibsen has published a review of what he called <a href="http://www.davsclaus.com/2020/12/apache-camel-37-lts-released-fastest.html">the fastest Camel ever!</a> So, go check it out if you want to know more about this camel release.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_tech_bytes">Tech bytes</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>A few interesting technical articles came out in the last weeks, so we’ll try to catch you up with three of them here. First, we have an excellent one from Bela Ban on <a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2020/12/running-jgroups-raft-as-service.html">running JGroups raft as a service</a>. It’s very hands on post, focusing on getting everything running. Then we have a longer walkthrough to let you experiment on <a href="https://blog.ramon-gordillo.dev/2020/12/spring-boot-embedded-cache-with-infinispan-in-kubernetes/">using Spring boot embedded cache with Infinispan on Kubernetes</a>. Certainly, worth a look, isn’t it? The last one is, of course, on Quarkus, because Quarkus is, as it should, all the rage lately. In this article, Clément Escoffier took the time to explain some of the <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/magic-control">magic beneath Quarkus and Vert.x</a> and why this is the kind magic you to have as a developer.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_evangelists_corner">Evangelist’s Corner</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As always, our very own Eric Schabell has been busy in the few last weeks and released a steady stream of new content. First, he published <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/01/codeready-containers-installing.html">part4 - Installing business automation operator</a> of his series on CodeReady containers. He then revisited the <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/12/codeready-containers-exploring-home-loan-mortgage-process.html">Home loan mortgage process using CodeReady Containers</a>. Still on the topic of CodeReady Containers, he provided a <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2021/01/codeready-containers-howto-setup-openshift-46-on-local-machine.html">How to setup the OpenShift Container Platform 4.6 on your local machine</a> follow by a tutorial on <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/12/codeready-containers-building-hr-process-with-openshift-operator.html">Building a Human Resources Process with an OpenShift Operator</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases_releases_releases">Releases, releases, releases…​</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As always, the JBoss community has been quite active in the last weeks, and more than a few project releases new version (including the forementionned Wildfly 22 and Apache Camel 3.7):</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2021/01/13/WildFly22-Final-Released/">Wildfly 22 Final released!</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2020/12/keycloak-1201-released.html">Keycloak 12.0.1 released</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://camel.apache.org/blog/2020/12/Camel37-Whatsnew/">Apache Camel 3.7</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://teiid.blogspot.com/2021/01/teiid-spring-boot-170-released.html">Teiid Spring Boot 1.7.0 Released</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_decaf">Decaf</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>You want to break from Java programming, but still learn something relevant to it? Well, take a look at this article on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2021/01/13/getting-started-with-tekton-and-pipelines/">Getting started with Tekton and Pipelines</a>. It’s more than likely to pique your interest.</p>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another installment of our JBoss editorial! Stay safe and healthy in the meantime.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="teiid" term="teiid"/>
        <category label="springboot" term="springboot"/>
        <category label="tekton" term="tekton"/>
        <category label="kubernetes" term="kubernetes"/>
        <category label="codeready" term="codeready"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="jgroups" term="jgroups"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss: 25 December 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-12-25.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-12-25.html"/>
        <updated>2020-12-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="Christmas, 2020">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss: 25 December 2020</h1>
      <p>I’m writing this on Christmas Day and have spent the last week or so thinking about what I should put
into my traditional 25th of December entry. Then it came to me in that "lightbulb moment": I’d replicate,
more or less, what I said to my entire team/org before I went on vacation a few days earlier. It’s a summary
of the year and I think it’s relevant for our wider community too. So here it is in a slightly modified form …​</p>
<p>I wanted to spend a few minutes thanking you all for the work and interactions you’ve done over this testing year!
I don’t think anyone could have predicted 2020 at the start of the year and I think it’s fair to say that every one of us
has been affected in one way or another. Yet if you look back on the year and the accomplishments we’ve achieved
as a community, you could be forgiven for thinking this was a normal year!</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Making Quarkus available to all OpenShift customers, which we announced at KubeCon, as well as continuing the innovation within
(e.g., Hibernate Reactive, RESTeasy Reactive);</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Knative/Serverless, where we now have 7 Working Group leads out of 15 in the Knative community, we also added Functions to OpenShift Serverless;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>More and more of our technologies become available to Kube developers;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We continued our close involvement with AdoptOpenJDK (aka Eclipse Adoptium), helping to push it to even greater heights;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>So many great innovations continued around efforts such as Kogito, Strimzi, Camel-K, Eclipse Vert.x, Infinispan, …​</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We all managed to host, attend, present at countless virtual conferences, workshops and Red Hat Summit; probably enough to realise what
we’re all missing from the real things!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Eclipse MicroProfile 4.0 and Eclipse Jakarta EE 9.0 both come to life;</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>The list could go on and on (e.g., EAP XD, OptaPlanner, …) but my point isn’t so much to call out the successes that this
community have helped to drive but rather to illustrate that we were able to do these and more at all! In the
climate of 2020, retaining the kind of focus we have and continuing to go above and beyond, as many of you and the teams
have, is a testament to Red Hat and our communities, our culture and the supporting bonds you’ve all built up and nurtured. For that
alone I thank you and you should all be incredibly proud!</p>
<p>With that in mind, whether or not you celebrate Christmas or intend to take extended time away, make sure you do take time
to rest and recharge. Be with your friends and family as much as you can given the continuing Covid situation. Find time to unwind
but also congratulate yourself on coming together in 2020 and delivering so much to our communities, partners and customers. I’m not
even going to try to predict what 2021 will be like but if we can replicate what we’ve been able to do in 2020, I’m sure
we’ll all come through it stronger and together!</p>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/mark-little.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Mark Little</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Little</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/mark-little</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Christmas" term="Christmas"/>
        <category label="2020" term="2020"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 17 December 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-12-17.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-12-17.html"/>
        <updated>2020-12-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, resteasy, springboot, avro, apicurio">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 17 December 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another installment of our JBoss Editorial and last before the holidays! As always during this period of the year, we all rush to finish our ongoing tasks so that we can enjoy a bit of rest. And the projects of the JBoss community do the same, which means we have quite of lot to discuss today! So, without any further ado…​</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_and_resteasy_reactive">Quarkus and RestEasy Reactive</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The last months have certainly been quite active for Quarkus. Now part of the portfolio of <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/topics/cloud-native-apps/what-is-quarkus">Red Hat products</a>, the project has everything but slow down. Just last week a new release, <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-10-3-final-released/">Quarkus 1.10.3</a> was published, but also RestEasy announced a large refactoring of its project <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/resteasy-reactive/">RestEasy Reactive</a> in order to integrate and support Quarkus even more. Alessio Soldano, one of the main developers of RestEasy, also shares his thoughts behind this project <a href="https://resteasy.github.io/2020/12/07/resteasy-reactive/">here</a>.</p>
<p>But that’s not all in the Quarkiverse! Andy Damevin released an interesting article on link:But that’s not all in the Quarkus-verse! Andy Damevin released an interesting article on new ways to discover Quarkus <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/extension-codestarts-a-new-way-to-learn-and-discover-quarkus/"> new ways to discover Quarkus using Extension codestarts</a>. Whether that you already know Quarkus or want to explore it for the first time, this one will be in any case quite interesting to you! Oh, and by the way Quarkiverse is by no means a "bon mot,” it’s the real thing: <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkiverse/">Quarkiverse Hub - Home of Community Extensions</a>, so go check out this article from George Gastaldi to know more about it!</p>
<p>Last, but certainly not the least, another article will help you <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/12/08/spring-boot-to-quarkus-migrations-and-more-in-red-hats-migration-toolkit-for-applications-5-1-0/">migrating your Spring Boot app to Quarkus using the Red Hat migration toolkit</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_apache_avro_and_apicurio_registry">Apache Avro and Apicurio Registry</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Avro and Apicurio got a lot of attention in the last weeks. First, Clément Escoffier, who already took the time to blog about <a href="">How to Use Kafka, Schema Registry and Avro with Quarkus</a> a few months ago, just released a new article on <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/avro-native/">Using Avro in a native executable</a>. Hugo Guerrero also took a stab at the topic in his blog entry on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/12/11/debezium-serialization-with-apache-avro-and-apicurio-registry/">Debezium serialization with Apache Avro and Apicurio Registry</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_decaf">Decaf'</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>With the end of 2020 coming up soon, it’s time to clean up our desk and prepare a clean slate for next year. So let’s do the same with our computer and follow <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/12/10/how-to-clean-up-the-fedora-root-folder/">this how-to to clean up your Fedora</a>!</p>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another installment of our JBoss editorial! Stay safe and healthy in the meantime.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="resteasy" term="resteasy"/>
        <category label="springboot" term="springboot"/>
        <category label="avro" term="avro"/>
        <category label="apicurio" term="apicurio"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 16 September 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-12-03.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-12-03.html"/>
        <updated>2020-12-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="jgroups, quarkus, infinispan, openshift, business automation">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 16 September 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Hello! Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial that brings you news and updates from our community.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases">Releases!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-10-2-final-released/">Quarkus 1.10</a> is out!
This release brings several updates, notably JSON as the default media type for REST resources in your Quarkus applications.
Now you no longer need all those <code>`@Produces</code> and <code>@Consumes</code> annotations!</p>
<p>Quarkus 1.10 also brings you two new Micrometer registries, additional metrics, and lots of consistency and configuration improvements to all things Swagger UI, which is detailed in the <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/stylish-api/">Stylish API</a> blog post.</p>
<p>WildFly have released <a href="https://www.wildfly.org/news/2020/11/27/WildFly-GraphQL-feature-pack-1.0/">GraphQL Feature Pack 1.0.0.Final</a> to give WildFly 20 and 21 the latest MicroProfile GraphQL and SmallRye GraphQL capabilities.
Congrats to the WildFly team!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_distributed_locks_they_dont_work">Distributed Locks? They Don’t Work!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Bela Ban’s recent post, <a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2020/11/i-hate-distributed-locks.html">I hate distributed locks!</a>, is an insightful and emotionally charged look at the pain and the agony of distributed locks.
He dissects different scenarios in which locks are distributed and the pitfalls for each.
Bela does give hints to other alternatives, but I’d suggest you go read them over on his blog.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_cloud_events_with_quarkus">Cloud Events with Quarkus</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Given that event-drive architectures are becoming ever more popular, Clement Escoffier introduces Cloud Events with the Kafka Connector in Quarkus and shows you <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/kafka-cloud-events/">how to write and read Cloud Events easily</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_vert_x_mutiny_api">Vert.x Mutiny API</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In another recent post on the Quarkus blog, <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/mutiny-vertx/">Mutiny and the Reactiverse</a>, Clement Escoffier explains using Mutiny variants of Vert.x APIs to get a seamless experience with reactive APIs in Quarkus while taking advantage of the Vert.x ecosystem.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_untangling_reactive_streams">Untangling Reactive Streams</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Continuing the discussion on the reactive paradigm, Rebecca Searls strips back complexities of Reactive Streams in her <a href="https://resteasy.github.io/2020/11/23/blog-Untangling-Reactive-Streams/">detailed blog post</a> and brings some clarity for wiring a Subscriber, Publisher, and Subscription.
Be sure to check out the demo code in <a href="https://github.com/rsearls/blog-posts">Rebecca’s github</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_business_automation_and_codeready_containers">Business Automation and CodeReady Containers</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In this first in his series of articles, Eric D. Schabell begins his journey that will guide you through using the latest Business Automation Operator on the OpenShift Container Platform.</p>
<p>Take a look at <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/12/codeready-containers-installing-business-automation-operator-part1.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+schabell/jboss+(Eric+D.Schabell-+JBoss)">CodeReady Containers - Installing business automation operator (Part 1)</a> to install the operator manually and then starting using decision management and process automation tooling on OpenShift.
Eric’s post is complete with an example project.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_infinispan_website">Infinispan Website</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The Infinispan community have launched a revamped site at <a href="https://infinispan.org">infinispan.org</a>.
The new layout has a great look and feel! Congrats to the team.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_red_hat_developer_highlights">Red Hat Developer Highlights</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Alex Krikos and Donna Smalls announce Red Hat Software Collections that offer use case-specific tools along with the most current, stable version of dynamic languages, open source databases, web servers, and other critical development components.
Visit the <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/12/01/red-hat-software-collections-3-6-now-generally-available/">Red Hat Software Collections 3.6 Now Generally Available</a> announcement.</p>
<p>David Harris and Nick Boldt’s <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/12/01/using-intellij-community-edition-in-red-hat-codeready-workspaces-2-5/">Using IntelliJ Community Edition in Red Hat CodeReady Workspaces 2.5</a> post explains how to create a custom workspace with IntelliJ IDEA in CodeReady Workspaces 2.5.</p>
<p>Karina Varela introduces us to the out-of-the-box integration with Apache Kafka in Process Automation Manager 7.9 in her artcile, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/27/red-hat-process-automation-manager-7-9-brings-apache-kafka-integration-and-more/">Red Hat Process Automation Manager 7.9 brings Apache Kafka integration and more</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="jgroups" term="jgroups"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="openshift" term="openshift"/>
        <category label="business automation" term="business automation"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This week in JBoss - 20th November 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-11-20.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-11-20.html"/>
        <updated>2020-11-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="news, weekly_update, weekly_editorial, wildfly, quarkus, jcliff, ansible, jca, jpa, jakarta-ee, openid, 3scale, event-driven, Camel-K, aws, kafka, camel, apicurio">
      <h1>This week in JBoss - 20th November 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p><em>Welcome to another installment of our JBoss Editorial! Today, we’ll focus on some core project of our community. The first one is obviously Wildfly, our Jakarta EE application server whom predecessor (JBoss AS) was the beginning of everything. The second one is our more recent and shiny project, Quarkus. Without any further ado, let’s begin!</em></p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wildfly_a_first_taste_of_jakarta_9">Wildfly, a first Taste of Jakarta 9</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>With the release of the <a href="https://wildfly.org//news/2020/11/19/WildFly2101-Released/">Wildfly 21.01</a>, it’s time to put the Jakarta EE server back in the spotlight. Especially as this release gives a <a href="https://www.wildfly.org//news/2020/11/12/Jakarta-EE-9-with-WildFly-Preview/">a preview of Jakarta EE 9</a>! And if your knowledge of the EE standards needs a refresher to fully enjoy this preview, we got you covered with this in depth two-part series on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/15/jakarta-ee-multitenancy-with-jpa-on-wildfly-part-1/">Jakarta EE multitenancy (part1)</a> and <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/12/jakarta-ee-multitenancy-with-jpa-on-wildfly-part-2/">(part 2)</a>.</p>
<p>But Jakarta EE 9 is not the only newsworthy item around Wildfly. The first part of my own series on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/06/wildfly-server-configuration-with-ansible-collection-for-jcliff-part-1/">automation of Wildfly using Ansible and JCliff</a> is out! It’s hand on a tutorial on how to set up Ansible and its decided collection for Wildfly (<a href="https://github.com/wildfly-extras/ansible_collections_jcliff">JCliff</a>) in order to fully automate the app server set up and configuration.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quarkus_leading_the_future_of_java">Quarkus, Leading the Future of Java</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>It might a bold statement, but we’ve made it! Or rather Red Hat made it as Quarkus 1.7 is available as a product for a little while now. Maybe it’s time to finally take a look at it by following this <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/10/leading-the-future-of-java-with-the-red-hat-build-of-quarkus-1-7/">Red Hat Quarkus tutorial</a>?</p>
<p>This is also a perfect opportunity to explore Quarkus functionality and ecosystems. For instance, take a look at this interesting post on <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/mutiny-invoke-and-call/">mutiny invoke and call</a>. Or simply explore the cloud readiness of the framework with this article on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/13/how-i-built-a-serverless-blog-search-with-java-quarkus-and-aws-lambda/">building a serverless blog search with Quarkus and AWS lambda</a> and this <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/introducing-quarkus-red-hat-openshift?sc_cid=701f2000000tyBjAAI">introduction to Quarkus on Red Hat Openshift</a>?</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_techbytes">Techbytes</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>If Quarkus and Wildfly did not quench your thirst for knowledge, let us give you a bit more nuggets. First, why not explore the topic of <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/09/openid-connect-integration-with-red-hat-3scale-api-management-and-okta/">using OpenID connect integration with 3scale</a>? Or maybe <a href="http://wei-meilin.blogspot.com/2020/11/contract-first-development-event-driven.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+blogspot%2FhFXzh+%28Christina+%E7%9A%84+J%E8%80%81%E9%97%86%29">contract first development using an event-driven approach with Kafka, AMQ Streams, APIcurio</a>? And to make it extra spicy, Christina has even a added a touch of Google protobuf! By the way, if "event driven" is your thing, you can then move this other article on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/17/event-driven-serverless-applications-with-camel-k/">event driven serverless with Camel K</a>.</p>
<p>Still hungry for more? Well, maybe it’s time for less crunchy and technical details? What about stepping back and invite some reflection on <a href="http://www.ofbizian.com/2020/11/open-source-monetization-ecosystem.html">Open Source monetization ecosystem</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases_releases_releases">Releases, releases, releases…​</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In case you somehow missed above (most likely by jumping directly to this section) …​ <a href="https://wildfly.org//news/2020/11/19/WildFly2101-Released/">Wildlfy 21 Alpha 1 has been released</a>!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_decaf">Decaf</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>All this Java made you too jittery? Time for a Java break? Here are a few dry cookies to go along your cup of joe. As mentioned above, the first part of my series on using [Ansible to automate Wildfly setup] might a nice palate cleanser. Also, if you are using Docker you might be interested in this article describing how to <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/19/transitioning-from-docker-to-podman/">transitioning from Docker to Podman</a>.</p>
<p><em>That’s all for today! Please join us again in two weeks for another installment of our JBoss editorial! Stay safe and healthy in the meantime.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
        <category label="weekly_update" term="weekly_update"/>
        <category label="weekly_editorial" term="weekly_editorial"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="jcliff" term="jcliff"/>
        <category label="ansible" term="ansible"/>
        <category label="jca" term="jca"/>
        <category label="jpa" term="jpa"/>
        <category label="jakarta-ee" term="jakarta-ee"/>
        <category label="openid" term="openid"/>
        <category label="3scale" term="3scale"/>
        <category label="event-driven" term="event-driven"/>
        <category label="Camel-K" term="Camel-K"/>
        <category label="aws" term="aws"/>
        <category label="kafka" term="kafka"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="apicurio" term="apicurio"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This week in JBoss - 6th November 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-11-06.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-11-06.html"/>
        <updated>2020-11-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="news, weekly_update, weekly_editorial, keycloak, camel, decision_manager, process_automation, wildfly, open_liberty, fabric8">
      <h1>This week in JBoss - 6th November 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial where we search through the JBoss Community for interesting articles and updates</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_optimizing_camel_3_7">Optimizing Camel 3.7</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Camel 3.7 continues the push to optimize camel core by introducing some more improvements including further modularisation to help reduce the size of the runtime, a lightweight mode and more.  For further details <a href="http://www.davsclaus.com/2020/11/apache-camel-37-more-camel-core.html">check out Claus' blog where he covers these improvements in more detail</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_keycloak_authentication_using_a_mobile_phone_number">Keycloak Authentication Using a Mobile Phone Number</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The Keycloak Identity and Access Management project provides an extension mechanism through which a developer can provide additional, custom authentication service providers to expand its capabilities.  <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/10/23/use-mobile-numbers-for-user-authentication-in-keycloak/">Siddhartha and his team recently took advantage of this capability to develop a custom authenticator class which could be used to authenticate a user via their mobile phone number</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_fronting_decision_management_with_a_node_js_front_end">Fronting Decision Management with a Node.js Front End</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>If you are interested in exploring how to expose the Decision Management server through a Node.js front end then Eric has a great demo for you.  The <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/10/codeready-containers-exploring-nodejs-with-decision-manager.html">demo is based on a bank loan scenario and uses numerous technologies within the Decision Management server as well as introducing a client application written in AngularJS and PatternFly</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wildfly_server_configuration_with_ansible_collection_for_jcliff">WildFly server configuration with Ansible collection for JCliff</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In the first part of a three part series covering how to take advantage of Ansible capabilities to fine tune a WildFly server, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/11/06/wildfly-server-configuration-with-ansible-collection-for-jcliff-part-1/">Romain walks us through the necessary steps for installing JCliff and ensuring it can be used within ansible playbooks</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_open_liberty_and_kerberosthanos_support">Open Liberty and Kerberos/Thanos support</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The Open Liberty 20.0.0.11 release introduced two very interesting capabilities, the addition of kerberos authentication for securing Java Database Connectivity data sources and the ability to visualise MicroProfile Metrics data from Thanos sources.  For more information on these capabilities <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/10/30/open-liberty-20-0-0-11-brings-kerberos-authentication-and-thanos-support-in-grafana-dashboards/">check out Austin’s blog on the topic</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_whats_new_in_fabric8_kubernetes_java_client">What’s new in Fabric8 Kubernetes Java Client</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>The recent Fabric8 Kubernetes Java client 4.12.0 release included a number of bug fixes and new features.  For more information on these updates, including details on some breaking changes, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/10/30/whats-new-in-fabric8-kubernetes-java-client-4-12-0/">head over to Rohan’s post where he covers these in more detail</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_jboss_online">JBoss Online</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Eric Schabell will be giving a presentation as part of the KieLives series on all technologies living under the KIE umbrella.  Eric’s talk is titled <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/11/kielive-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-rules-processes-episode14.html">"The ultimate beginers guide to rules and processes"</a> and will be taking place on November 10th.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_new_releases">New Releases</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://www.keycloak.org/">Keycloak team</a> have announced the release of <a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2020/11/keycloak-1103-released.html">Keycloak 11.0.3</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>That’s all for this edition of the JBoss Editorial, please join us in a couple of weeks when we will bring you more news and articles from the JBoss Community Projects.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/kevin-conner.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Kevin Conner</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Conner</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/kevin-conner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
        <category label="weekly_update" term="weekly_update"/>
        <category label="weekly_editorial" term="weekly_editorial"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="decision_manager" term="decision_manager"/>
        <category label="process_automation" term="process_automation"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="open_liberty" term="open_liberty"/>
        <category label="fabric8" term="fabric8"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This week in JBoss - 23rd October 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-10-23.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-10-23.html"/>
        <updated>2020-10-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="news, weekly_update, weekly_editorial, kafka, quarkus, infinispan, keycloak, openshift, micrometer, microprofile, mutiny, codeready">
      <h1>This week in JBoss - 23rd October 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial where we bring you articles and news from across the JBoss Community of projects.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_micrometer_is_recommended_for_metrics_with_quarkus_1_9">Micrometer is recommended for metrics with Quarkus 1.9</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/micrometer-metrics/">this post</a>, Ken explains why the Quarkus team are now reccomending the use of the Micrometer Quarkus extension over the previous Eclipse MicroProfile Metrics extension.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kafka_how_to_fail_gracefully">Kafka - How to fail gracefully</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Failures are inevitable.
There is nothing we can do about that, and that also applies to Kafka applications.
Your application may contain a faulty component misbehaving once in a while, or unable to process a specific Kafka record.
In <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/kafka-failure-strategy/">this post</a>, Clement explains how to manage these failures.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_use_mobile_numbers_for_user_authentication_in_keycloak">Use mobile numbers for user authentication in Keycloak</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/10/23/use-mobile-numbers-for-user-authentication-in-keycloak/">this post</a> Siddhartha De explains how to extend Keycloak to use mobile-based authentication.
The post explains the need for mobile-authentication and shows, hands on, how to use the Keycloak service provider interface to create this extension.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_securely_connect_quarkus_and_red_hat_data_grid_on_red_hat_openshift">Securely connect Quarkus and Red Hat Data Grid on Red Hat OpenShift</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Continuing on the theme of security, James Falkner explains (<a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/10/15/securely-connect-quarkus-and-red-hat-data-grid-on-red-hat-openshift/">here</a>) how to secure applications deployed on Red Hat OpenShift that use the <a href="https://quarkus.io/guides/infinispan-client">Quarkus Data Grid Extension</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_creating_a_payments_architecture">Creating a Payments Architecture</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Eric continues his blog series looking at how Cloud technologies are changing the way we architect and deliver software, in particular how these technologies will apply to the Payment Services industry.
This week Eric describes a <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/10/payments-architecture-financial-calculations-example.html">Financial Calculations Example</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_mutiny_how_does_retry_retries">Mutiny - How does retry…​ retries?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Clement was recently helping a community Quarkus user understand how to retry asynchronous operations with Mutiny.
In doing so, he realised it was not all that simple to understand, and so he created <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/uni-retry/">this blog post</a> so that the whole community could benefit from his explanation.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_codeready_containers_building_a_cloud_native_human_resources_process">CodeReady Containers - Building a Cloud-Native Human Resources Process</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>In <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/10/codeready-containers-building-cloud-native-hr-process.html">this blog post</a> Eric talks you through how to install process automation developer tooling into a running Openshift Container platform.
You can also refer to one of <a href="https://gitlab.com/redhatdemocentral/ocp-install-demo">Eric’s previous posts</a> for details on how to easily get Openshift Container Platform running on your local machine.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_new_releases">New Releases</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://quarkus.io/">Quarkus team</a> have announced the release of <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-9-0-final-released/">Quarkus 1.9</a> and <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/intellij-quarkus-tools-1.2.0/">Quarkus Tools for IntelliJ 1.2.0</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/paul-robinson.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Paul Robinson</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robinson</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/paul-robinson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
        <category label="weekly_update" term="weekly_update"/>
        <category label="weekly_editorial" term="weekly_editorial"/>
        <category label="kafka" term="kafka"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="openshift" term="openshift"/>
        <category label="micrometer" term="micrometer"/>
        <category label="microprofile" term="microprofile"/>
        <category label="mutiny" term="mutiny"/>
        <category label="codeready" term="codeready"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This week in JBoss - 12th October 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-10-12.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-10-12.html"/>
        <updated>2020-10-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="news, weekly_update, weekly_editorial, decision_manager, process_automation, kafka, camel, kamlets, quarkus, hacktoberfest, infinispan">
      <h1>This week in JBoss - 12th October 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial where we bring you articles and news from across the JBoss Community of projects</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_creating_a_payments_architecture">Creating a Payments Architecture</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>With Cloud technologies changing the way we architect and deliver software Eric has been taking a look at how these technologies will apply to the Payment Services industry.</p>
<p>In the next two posts from his Payment Architecture series Eric introduces us to <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/10/payments-architecture-anti-money-laundering-example.html">the design of an Anti-Money Laundering solution</a> and follows that with <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/10/payments-architecture-fraud-detection-example.html">the design of a Fraud Detection solution</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_codeready_containers_decision_manager_and_process_automation">CodeReady Containers, Decision Manager and Process Automation</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>If you have ever wanted to explore Decision Manager or Process Automation running within the cloud then it has never been easier to get started.  Eric has developed two simple setups, both leveraging CodeReady containers and OpenShift Container Platform 4.5, which allow you to quickly set up <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/10/codeready-containers-getting-started-with-ocp-45-and-decision-manager-tooling.html">Decision Manager</a> and <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/10/codeready-containers-ocp-45-with-process-automation-tooling.html">Process Automation</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kafka_and_emitters_a_deeper_dive">Kafka and Emitters, a deeper dive</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Following on from an earlier blog post introducing us to emitters and how they can be used to send messages, Clement has taken a <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/reactive-messaging-emitter/">deeper look into the Emitter construct and explains how this can be used to bridge between the imperative and reactive worlds</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_optimizing_camel_3_6">Optimizing Camel 3.6</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Camel 3.6 will bring with it a number of optimizations to the camel core which will improve not only the performance of the core but also reduce the resources required to run camel routes.  For more information <a href="http://www.davsclaus.com/2020/10/apache-camel-36-more-camel-core.html">check out Claus' blog where he describes the changes in more detail</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_kamlets_camel_in_the_cloud">Kamlets, Camel in the cloud</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Apache Camel K 1.2.0 introduced a number of features, the most important of which is the Kamelet.  The Kamelet represents a camel route snippet and encapsulates the logic for connecting to a specific system.  For more information check out <a href="https://www.nicolaferraro.me/2020/10/12/kamelets/">Nicola’s blog where he introduces you to Kamelets and how they relate to Knative Eventing</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_testing_quarkus">Testing Quarkus</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Alex Soto and Burr Sutter recently gave a talk about testing Quarkus applications as part of the DevNation Tech Talk series.  The talk covers <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/10/12/quarked-testing-writing-tests-for-quarkus/">how to test basic components as well as more advanced topics such as persistence, service virtualization and using containers for testing</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_contributing_to_opensource_communities">Contributing to OpenSource Communities</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>With <a href="https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/">Hacktoberfest</a> already under way there are a number of opportunities for contributing to OpenSource, including a number of projects within the JBoss Community with two of those being <a href="https://strimzi.io">Strimzi</a> and <a href="https://quarkus.io/">Quarkus</a>.   If you are interested in <a href="https://strimzi.io/blog/2020/10/01/hacktoberfest/">contributing to Strimzi</a> then check out Paolo’s post, if interested in <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/contributing-for-the-first-time/">contributing to Quarkus</a> then check out Loïc’s post.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_new_releases">New Releases</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://quarkus.io/">Quarkus team</a> have announced the release of <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-8-2-final-released/">Quarkus 1.8.2.Final</a> and <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-8-3-final-released/">Quarkus 1.8.3.Final</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://infinispan.org/">Infinispan</a> team have announced the release of <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/09/08/infinispan-12/">Infinispan 12.0.0.Dev03</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>That’s all for this episode of the JBoss Editorial, please join us for our next edition when we will take another spin through the JBoss Community Projects in search of more interesting news and articles.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/kevin-conner.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Kevin Conner</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Conner</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/kevin-conner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
        <category label="weekly_update" term="weekly_update"/>
        <category label="weekly_editorial" term="weekly_editorial"/>
        <category label="decision_manager" term="decision_manager"/>
        <category label="process_automation" term="process_automation"/>
        <category label="kafka" term="kafka"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="kamlets" term="kamlets"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="hacktoberfest" term="hacktoberfest"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 30 September 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-09-30.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-09-30.html"/>
        <updated>2020-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="jBPM, OCP, OpenShift, Camel, CamelK, DevConf, Kafka">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 30 September 2020</h1>
      <p>It’s that time again where we round up the latest news from the community…</p>
<p>Are you looking to develop projects on your local machine, and push them on to a real OpenShift Container Platform, without having to worry about cloud hosting of your container platform?
In this <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/09/how-to-setup-openshift-container-platform-45.html">post</a> Eric Schabell provides an easy way to get up and running with CodeReady containers on your own development machine.
He’s automated most of the process through scripts, and guides you through the rest of the process.
Eric also shows you how to drop into the Developer console in OCP providing a developer focused view that hides much of the plumbing that is not needed during development.</p>
<p>In this <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/09/28/call-an-existing-rest-service-with-apache-camel-k/">post</a> Mary Cochran shows us a simple way to connect existing services together using CamelK via each service’s REST APIs.
Mary gets deep into the details providing code examples and commands to get you up and running.</p>
<p>Eric Schabell continues his <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/09/financial-payments-architecture-an-introduction.html">blog series</a>, bringing you architectural blueprints for&nbsp;cloud-native financial payment services.
The blueprints are focused on proven interactions, messaging, processing, and integration patterns that you can put to use when building a cloud-native payment architecture.
This week he covers the <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/09/payments-architecture-common-elements.html">Common Architecture Elements</a> that make up the architecture, and gets into some details with the <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/09/payments-architecture-immediate-payments-example.html">Immediate Payments Example</a>.</p>
<p>As is normal for this time of year, the conference season is beginning to kick off.
Albeit this year in a virtual arena.
Undoubtedly this is an unfortunate situation for those that enjoy the in-person events.
However, it’s great for accessibility and reach allowing many more people across to globe to attend.
DevConf.US 2020 is one such event.
It’s a free, Red Hat sponsored technology conference for community project and professional contributors to Free and Open Source technologies.
Read more <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/09/devconfus-2020-appdev-containerization-ask-the-experts.html">here</a> where Eric describes the “AppDev &amp; Containerization Ask the Experts” Panels that he and Kurt Stam  will be moderating.</p>
<p>This week Kapil Shukla explains how to <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/09/28/build-a-data-streaming-pipeline-using-kafka-streams-and-quarkus/">build a data streaming pipeline using Kafka Streams and Quarkus</a>.
In this post Kapil shows how data can be processed in real-time as and when it arrives, instead of being batch processed as was needed in the past.</p>
<p>In this <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/09/22/troubleshooting-user-task-errors-in-red-hat-process-automation-manager-and-red-hat-jboss-bpm-suite/">Post</a> Anton Giertli provides help with troubleshooting user task errors in Red Hat Process Automation Manager and Red Hat JBoss BPM Suite.
If you are a developer working with user tasks and having trouble debugging them, this post might well help you out.</p>
<p>With the recent release of Apache Camel VS Code extension (0.0.27) comes several new language support features for Apache Camel.
Read this <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/09/18/new-language-support-features-in-apache-camel-vs-code-extension-0-0-27/">post</a> to learn more.</p>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/paul-robinson.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Paul Robinson</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robinson</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/paul-robinson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="jBPM" term="jBPM"/>
        <category label="OCP" term="OCP"/>
        <category label="OpenShift" term="OpenShift"/>
        <category label="Camel" term="Camel"/>
        <category label="CamelK" term="CamelK"/>
        <category label="DevConf" term="DevConf"/>
        <category label="Kafka" term="Kafka"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 16 September 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-09-16.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-09-16.html"/>
        <updated>2020-09-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="jgroups, quarkus, infinispan">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 16 September 2020</h1>
      <p>Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial where we gather news from our communities and explore developments from our projects.</p>
<p>Our very own Mark Little goes into detail to explain Quarkus and Jakarta EE compatibility. Mark gives an insightful breakdown of the history for both projects and answers a much asked question, will Quarkus and Jarkata EE come together? No spoilers here, though. Go read Mark’s <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/09/11/quarkus-and-jakarta-ee-together-or-not/">Quarkus and Jakarta EE: Together, or not?</a> if you already haven’t.</p>
<p>In the evangelist’s corner, Eric Schabell has brought out an excellent <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/09/beginners-guide-to-decision-management-retail-web-shop.html">hands-on workshop with labs</a> for Red Hat Decision Manager that show you how to design and build a retail web shop from scratch.</p>
<p>Eric also teams up with Ramon Villarreal to bring you architectural blueprints for <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/09/financial-payments-architecture-an-introduction.html">cloud-native financial payment services</a>. The blueprints are focused on proven interactions, messaging, processing, and integration patterns that you can put to use when building a cloud-native payment architecture.</p>
<p>Leon Matthews continues the topic of all things financial with his analysis of the history of Java in the banking sector and the role Quarkus is playing in allowing banks and financial institutions to embrace change, innovate to remain competitive, and become more efficient. Read Leon’s post: <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/25-years-and-going-strong-why-java-matters-future-banks?source=bloglisting">25 years and going strong: Why Java matters to the future of banks</a>.</p>
<p>Speaking of Quarkus, Clement Escoffier shows you how to build a stream of beer and then retrieve beers in a reactive way. After walking you through how you can do that with Mutiny, Clement provides a gist with all the code that you can compile and execute with jbang and a single command. You can find everything in his <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/mutiny-pagination/">Handling paginated APIs with Mutiny</a> post.</p>
<p>Another post from the Quarkus team that is worth reading is Jeff Beck’s <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/wipro-customer-story/">Wipro Addresses Seismic Shift in Retail with Quarkus</a>. Jeff shares the Wipro story by describing their needs and challenges and how they adopted Quarkus to modernize their applications and address customer use cases.</p>
<p>If it hasn’t crossed your radar, Bela Ban shows us his plans for a <a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2020/09/one-size-fits-all-jgroups.html">One Size Fits All JGroups</a> program and explains what is needed to get there.</p>
<p>Jakub Scholz on the Strimzi team shares a post that looks at using the <a href="https://strimzi.io/blog/2020/09/01/enforce-custom-resource-policies-with-opa-gatekeeper/">Open Policy Agent Gatekeeper project to enforce policies when creating custom resources</a> and demonstrates how this is useful. While the post focuses on Strimzi, Jakub points out how Gatekeeper can be used with other projects so go take a look.</p>
<p>Releases!!</p>
<p>Congratulations to the Infinispan team for releasing the Dev03 cut of Infinispan 12. Cross-site replication capabilities continue to advance with an SPI that includes configurable policies for merging conflicting values from asynchronous backups, a feature which guarantees data consistency between global Infinispan clusters. That’s no small feat of engineering! Find out about that and more over on the <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/09/08/infinispan-12/">Infinispan blog</a>.</p>
<p>Quarkus 1.8 is out with some shiny new features, including jbang integration for easy Quarkus-based scripting, support for multiple persistence units for the Hibernate ORM extension, a new Micrometer extension, and update to GraalVM 20.2 for building native apps from Quarkus projects. Here is the <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-8-0-final-released/">announcement with all the info</a>.</p>
<p>Keycloak have announced their new Account Console, built on React and PatternFly 4. The latest version offers a fresher look and feel with custom themes and extensions. Go <a href="https://www.keycloak.org/2020/09/new-account-console.adoc">check it out</a>.</p>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="jgroups" term="jgroups"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JBoss Weekly Editorial 27 August 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-08-27.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-08-27.html"/>
        <updated>2020-08-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="openshift, openjdk, amq, strimzi, automation, kubernetes, keycloak">
      <h1>JBoss Weekly Editorial 27 August 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Weekly Editorial!
Summer is drawing to a close, but that doesn’t mean Red Hat has been resting, or that nothing has been happening over the past two weeks.
There’s been some great movement and progress made, which we’ll cover.
In this edition we’re going to focus on OpenShift, the blogosphere, and finally, other project news.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_openshift">OpenShift</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Last week was KubeCon Europe 2020, which as you can guess, was a big event for OpenShift!
We had 15 speakers from Red Hat speaking over the three days, giving 17 talks.
A number of new announcements, blog posts, and articles came out during KubeCon Europe 2020, They’re all liked at <a href="https://www.openshift.com/kubecon">the OpenShift event page</a>.
There’s simply too many to link here.
The above event page has videos, press release links, links to other announcements and blogs.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_blogs">Blogs</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Continuing the trend about OpenShift, Paul Vergilis wrote about external clients and Red Hat AMQ over at the <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/08/26/connecting-external-clients-to-red-hat-amq-broker-on-red-hat-openshift/">Red Hat Developer blog</a>.
If you’re interested in getting started with Strimzi, Apache Kafka on Kubernetes, you’ll want to catch up on the blog post Paolo Patierno and Jakub Scholz wrote: <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/08/14/introduction-to-strimzi-apache-kafka-on-kubernetes-kubecon-europe-2020/">Introduction to Strimzi: Apache Kafka on Kubernetes (KubeCon Europe 2020)</a>.
For those of you running OpenJDK 8, you’ll want to know more about JDK Flight Recorder available in OpenJDK 8u262. An indepth intro is available at the <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/08/25/get-started-with-jdk-flight-recorder-in-openjdk-8u/">Red Hat Developer Blog</a> written by Mario Torre.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_projects">Projects</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>To wrap up this edition, we will be looking at two announcements from Keycloak:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2020/08/keycloak-1101-released.html">Keycloak 11.0.1 released</a> - fixing seven bugs</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2020/08/sunsetting-louketo-project.adoc.html">Sunsetting Louketo Project</a> - Bruno Oliveira discusses the reasons in this blog post.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>We’re natuarally happy for a new release and sad for Louketo.</p>
<p>Thanks for being here with us in this edition!
We look forward to seeing you again in two weeks.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/jason-porter.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Jason Porter</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Porter</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/jason-porter</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="openshift" term="openshift"/>
        <category label="openjdk" term="openjdk"/>
        <category label="amq" term="amq"/>
        <category label="strimzi" term="strimzi"/>
        <category label="automation" term="automation"/>
        <category label="kubernetes" term="kubernetes"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 13 August 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-08-13.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-08-13.html"/>
        <updated>2020-08-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="jgroups, quarkus, keycloak, skupper, tech talk, infinispan, strimzi">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 13 August 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial where we gather news from our communities and explore developments from our projects.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_jgroups_5">JGroups 5!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Exciting news from Bela Ban as <a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2020/08/jgroups-500final-released.html">JGroups 5.0.0.Final</a> is released. JGroups 5 brings lots of improvements and some major API changes.</p>
<p>Perhaps the biggest change is that <a href="http://www.jgroups.org/manual5/index.html#Message"><code>Message</code></a> is now an interface with a number of subclasses that perform late marshalling so object payload is serialized at the point when messages are sent, which eliminates a memory allocation and makes JGroups performance even better.</p>
<p>Other cool features in JGroups 5 are <a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2020/07/double-your-performance-virtual-threads.html">virtual thread support</a>, an implementation of the Random Early Drop (RED) protocol, more efficient FD_ALL3 failure detection, a new protocol to dump stats, and lots more.</p>
<p>Hearty congratulations to Bela and all the contributors and folks who made it happen!!</p>
<p>Head over to the <a href="http://www.jgroups.org/manual5/index.html">JGroups 5 documentation</a> and find out more.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_keycloak_tech_talk">Keycloak Tech Talk</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Stian Thorgersen of the Keycloak team presents a DevNation Tech Talk that provides an in-depth look at the best open-source identity and management solution around. Stian gives a great demo of Keycloak that not only highlights features but showcases just how easy it is to integrate and use Keycloak capabilities to secure your applications.</p>
<p>Spend half an hour and let Stian dazzle you with <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/08/07/a-deep-dive-into-keycloak/">A deep dive into Keycloak</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_reactive_quarkus_a_java_mutiny">Reactive Quarkus: A Java Mutiny</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Another Tech Talk that you should definitely check out comes from Clement Escoffier and Edson Yanaga, who go into detail about Mutiny, a new reactive programming library. Clement and Edson explain why reactive matters, how Mutiny is makes it easier to develop reactive applications, and how the library is integrated with Quarkus.</p>
<p>Listen to Clement and Edson deliver their excellent talk, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/08/07/reactive-quarkus-a-java-mutiny/">Reactive Quarkus: A Java Mutiny</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_skupper_and_the_hybrid_cloud">Skupper and the Hybrid Cloud</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>By now I’m sure you’ve heard of <a href="https://skupper.io/">Skupper</a> but maybe have yet to see it in action. Ted Ross gives a great introduction and live demonstration of Skupper across AWS, GCP, and Azure that shows real-time load balancing and fail-over.</p>
<p>Watch Ted’s <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/08/10/kubernetes-and-the-hybrid-cloud-with-skupper/">Kubernetes and the hybrid cloud with Skupper</a> Tech Talk today. You won’t regret it.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_in_the_community">In the Community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Katia Aresti has created a pretty awesome Infinispan Server tutorial that demonstrates a full set of capabilities with a weather application. Visit the <a href="https://infinispan.org/infinispan-server-tutorial/">Infinispan Remote Weather App Tutorial</a> and try it for yourself.</p>
<p>Jakub Scholz on the Strimzi team has written a comprehensive blog post, <a href="https://strimzi.io/blog/2020/08/05/using-open-policy-agent-with-strimzi-and-apache-kafka/">Using Open Policy Agent with Strimzi and Apache Kafka</a>, that explores support for Kafka authorization using Open Policy Agent.</p>
<p>That’s it for this week’s editorial. Thanks for reading and see you next time.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="jgroups" term="jgroups"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="skupper" term="skupper"/>
        <category label="tech talk" term="tech talk"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="strimzi" term="strimzi"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 30th July 2020: No rest for the JBoss community!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-07-30.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-07-30.html"/>
        <updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="eap, editorial, infinispan, quarkus, jgroups, java, wildfly, clustering, mod_cluster, eclipse, jkube, kubernetes,">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 30th July 2020: No rest for the JBoss community!</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another installment of our JBoss Editorial! The last two weeks have been pretty rich on published content and releases, so let’s dive right in!</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_from_spring_boot_to_quarkus">From Spring Boot to Quarkus</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As Quarkus community is increasing the question of how to migrate to this new framework (or rather runtime) often arises. If you happen to have such predicament with Spring Boot, I’m sure you’ll be quite interested to read this article on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/07/17/migrating-spring-boot-tests-to-quarkus/">migrating Spring Boot tests to Quarkus</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_secure_vue_js_with_keycloak">Secure vue.js with Keycloak</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>If most of the content we mentioned today is made of articles, we have one, quite cool video content to share. It’s coming straight from one of the tech-talks of the DevNation and we hope you’ll like it :  <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/devnation/tech-talks/secure-vuejs-keycloak">Secure vue.js using Keycloak</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_jgroups_double_your_performance_with_virtual_threads">JGroups: Double your performance with virtual threads!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Quite a lot of exciting things are happening in the realm of JGroups lately! Last time, we already mentioned the <a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2020/06/new-netty-transport.html">new netty transport</a>, but Bela Ban, the creator of project, got us even more excited with this news about <a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2020/07/double-your-performance-virtual-threads.html">how one can double its performance using virtual threads (fibers) on JDK15/16</a>!!! This JDK is still a bit down the road, but its certainly a nice glimpse into tomorrow.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_back_to_the_basics">Back to the Basics</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As said above, the last two weeks have been particularly rich in interesting content around the JBoss community and the Java ecosystem at large. Some of those articles took the time to go back and rethink some aspects of our work that we take for granted. Let’s first mention this original take on java programming that focuses on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/07/09/behavior-is-easy-state-is-hard-tame-inconsistent-state-in-your-java-code/">taming inconsistent state in a Java code</a>.</p>
<p>This first article is already pretty centered around coding, but this next one goes into the very guts of Infinispan! If you know the project, I’m sure you’ll find this entry on <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/07/22/anchored-keys/">anchored keys</a> as fascinating as I did!</p>
<p>Let’s also revisit a classic: load balancing a JEE app server (such as Wildfly or its product counterpart JBoss EAP), but with a twist: <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/07/15/load-balancing-red-hat-jboss-enterprise-application-platform-subclusters-with-mod_cluster/">Load balancing Red Hat JBoss EAP with subclusters</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_evangelists_corner">Evangelist’s Corner</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>No rest for the wicked! And no, no rest for our very own Eric D. Schabell! In the last two weeks, he has been quite busy again. First of all, he got his very <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/07/what-the-dev-podcast-episode-44-agile-integration.html">first interview on a podcast</a> (yep, that’s right, he was never on a podcast before!). With the host, he discussed the best practices for Agile integration. If you are interested in this topic, fetch the episode, you won’t regret it!</p>
<p>That’s not all. Eric also took the time to update and release his "fully updated to the latest release" version of his <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/07/beginners-guide-building-a-retail-web-shop-workshop-update.html">Beginners guide - Building a retail web shop workshop update</a>.</p>
<p>On top of that, he took the time to describe <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/07/how-to-install-rhpam-77.html">how to How to Install Red Hat Process Automation Manager 7.7</a> and share his experience with the <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/07/shift-remote-2020-devops-heroes.html">Shift Remote 2020 online conference</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases_releases_releases">Releases, releases, releases,…​</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As always, the JBoss community has been pretty busy in the last weeks and a few projects have seized the relative quietness of Summer to release new version of their product:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2020/07/keycloak-1100-released.html">Keycloak 11.0.0</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://bytemanblog.blogspot.com/2020/07/byteman-4012-has-been-released.html">Byteman 4.0.12</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/07/27/infinispan-12/">Infinispan 12.0.0.Dev01</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_decaf">Decaf</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>For once, this section stays rather close to Java, covering how to <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/07/27/deploy-your-java-web-application-into-the-cloud-using-eclipse-jkube/">deploy your Java Webapp into the cloud using Eclipse JKube</a>. So, yes, we’ll talk Kubernetes, but in a context quite close to home :) .</p>
<p>That’s all for another edition of the JBoss Editorial, please join us again for more exciting development from the JBoss Communities.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="eap" term="eap"/>
        <category label="editorial" term="editorial"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="jgroups" term="jgroups"/>
        <category label="java" term="java"/>
        <category label="wildfly" term="wildfly"/>
        <category label="clustering" term="clustering"/>
        <category label="mod_cluster" term="mod_cluster"/>
        <category label="eclipse" term="eclipse"/>
        <category label="jkube" term="jkube"/>
        <category label="kubernetes" term="kubernetes"/>
        <category label="" term=""/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 9 July 2020: Over the (j)cliff!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-07-09.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-07-09.html"/>
        <updated>2020-07-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, editorial, infinispan, jgroups, netty, codeready, serverless, microservice, ansible, jcliff, widlfy, eap, eap-xp, microprofile">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 9 July 2020: Over the (j)cliff!</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another installment of our JBoss Editorial! Summer has begun, well, at least for those of you readers living in the northern hemisphere :)! So let’s enjoy it by giving some nice, interesting and exciting reading material to enjoy while resting in the sun (with your mask, #staysafe!).</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_infinispan_11">Infinispan 11!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>It’s out! The new major version of Infinispan is here! Please go and check out <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/07/03/infinispan-11/">Infinispan 11</a>!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_jgroups_new_netty_transport">JGroups: new Netty transport!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>I’ve said it many times, JGroups is an incredible piece of software. The power and the flexibility of the frameworks always dazzle me, so I’m very excited about this <a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2020/06/new-netty-transport.html">new netty transport</a> getting into it!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_ansible_collection_for_jcliff">Ansible Collection for JCliff</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>It’s a pet project of mine that I have already mentioned a few months ago: Andrew Block, Roel Holzmans and I have been working on integrating further Widlfy (and EAP) into Ansible, in order to ensure that one can use the tool to fine-tune as much as possible the JEE server’s configuration. We leverage an existing Open Source Java tool called <a href="https://github.com/bserdar/jcliff">JCliff</a> to just that.</p>
<p>Last year, we released a role, already available in <a href="https://galaxy.ansible.com/redhat-cop/jcliff">Ansible Galaxy</a>, to integrate JCliff into Ansible. However, since then, the Ansible community released a new format to distribute extension, called Ansible Collection. We therefore decide to migrate our content there and we finally released, just this week, a very first version: <a href="https://galaxy.ansible.com/redhat/jcliff">Ansible Collection for JCliff 0.0.1</a>.</p>
<p>So, please check it out! All you need to do is $ ansible-galaxy collection install redhat.jcliff:0.0.1 and, voilà, the collection is installed and you can start to <a href="https://github.com/ansible-middleware/ansible_collections_jcliff_demo">play with it</a>.</p>
<p>Oh, almost forgot! This release also supports, on tops of Linux, MacOSX with homebrew! (Windows using Chocolatey is coming next).</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_serverless_and_microservice">Serverless and Microservice</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>As alluring as “serverless” is, it does, like any other technology, come with its own challenges. Follow Christina as she goes through the importance of having the proper infrastructure to support your “serverless” apps in this well thought out blog entry: <a href="http://wei-meilin.blogspot.com/2020/07/serverless-integration-components.html">Serverless Integration Components</a></p>
<p>Follow this first read, you may want to take a look at this other article on <a href="http://www.ofbizian.com/2020/07/operators-and-sidecars-are-new-model.html">operators and sidecars are the new model</a>, which also discuss similar concerns.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_microprofile">Microprofile</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>With the release JBoss EAP XP, there are a lot of opportunities to develop supported microprofile application. So if you want to explore how to develop such an application, please follow <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/author/ehugonne/">Emmanuel Hugonnet</a>’s tutorial on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/07/01/develop-eclipse-microprofile-applications-on-red-hat-jboss-enterprise-application-platform-expansion-pack-1-0-with-red-hat-codeready-workspaces/">Develop Eclipse MicroProfile applications on Red Hat JBoss Enterprise Application Platform Expansion Pack 1.0 with Red Hat CodeReady Workspaces</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_decafquarkus_workshops_automated_with_ansible">Decaf—Quarkus Workshops automated with Ansible</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Yeah, I know, we just talked about Ansible! Where is my Java stuff you are rightly asking. Well, as you’ll see Ansible, while being Python, plays well with Java software, as demonstrated by this article on <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/07/03/automate-workshop-setup-with-ansible-playbooks-and-codeready-workspaces/">automate workshop setup with Ansible playbooks and CodeReady workspaces</a>.</p>
<p>That’s all for another edition of the JBoss Editorial, please join us again for more exciting development from the JBoss Communities.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/romain-pelisse.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Romain Pelisse</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romain Pelisse</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/romain-pelisse</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="editorial" term="editorial"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="jgroups" term="jgroups"/>
        <category label="netty" term="netty"/>
        <category label="codeready" term="codeready"/>
        <category label="serverless" term="serverless"/>
        <category label="microservice" term="microservice"/>
        <category label="ansible" term="ansible"/>
        <category label="jcliff" term="jcliff"/>
        <category label="widlfy" term="widlfy"/>
        <category label="eap" term="eap"/>
        <category label="eap-xp" term="eap-xp"/>
        <category label="microprofile" term="microprofile"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss: 26 June 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-06-26.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-06-26.html"/>
        <updated>2020-06-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, data grid, camel, editorial,">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss: 26 June 2020</h1>
      <p>Here we are, once again at the close of June.
Another summer has begun, albeit a little different than most.
I hope everyone is safe, healthy, and doing well.
There have been some very interesting blogs posted in the past couple of weeks that we’ll discuss in this edition, as well as a few releases.</p>
<p>Operators in Kubernetes provide an extension point for the platform.
They follow a pattern allowing you to manage resources and applications within the cluster.
An operator can be either namespace-scoped or cluster-scoped.
Did you know, however, that you can convert between the two?
That is exactly what Abhishek Koserwal details in six steps over on the <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/26/migrating-a-namespace-scoped-operator-to-a-cluster-scoped-operator/">Red Hat Developer blog</a>.
Abhishek walks you through a basic example and provides the full example as a GitHub repo.
Read the article for more information, and reasons why you may want or need to switch between the different scopes.</p>
<p>Multitenancy may be something you deal with everyday, or it may be something you’re looking at adding to your current application base.
Either way, dealing with persistence can be tricky.
Tenants must not see each other’s data, but be allowed to operate simultaneously.
Your application must also perform well while still being easy to maintain.
Rhuan Rocha has started a two part series on how to use JPA with Multitenancy over on the Red Hat Developer blog.
<a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/15/jakarta-ee-multitenancy-with-jpa-on-wildfly-part-1/">The first entry</a> details the problem and presents a possible solution using WildFly and EJBs.
Expect the next installment to look more at Hibernate and JPA solutions.</p>
<p>Effortlessly building a native application is of course, one of the amazing capabilities of Quarkus.
However, when it comes to debugging, a native Quarkus application makes debugging <strong>very</strong> difficult.
A large part of this is the optimizations that happen to create that quick, small, native binary.
This debugging complication hasn’t gone unnoticed.
Andrew Dinn has been working on this problem.
He contributed a solution where the debug information is embedded with in the native image and can be access with <code>gdb</code>.
If you’d like to learn more about the solution, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/25/debugging-graalvm-native-images-using-gdb/">read Andrew’s blog entry</a>.</p>
<p>Continuing with the Quarkus theme, Durgesh Anaokar wrote about <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/19/develop-and-test-a-quarkus-client-on-red-hat-codeready-containers-with-red-hat-data-grid-8-0/">developing and testing a Quarkus Red Hat Data Grid client using Red Hat CodeReady Containers</a>.
Durgesh details installing CRC (Red Hat Code Ready Containers) and Data Grid on OpenShift 4 as well as running the client.
Naturally, his project code is hosted in GitHub, you’ll find that link in his blog entry.</p>
<p>Red Hat now has images, Universal Base Images to be exact, of OpenJDK (8 and 11) in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 8.2.
A Universal Base Image (UBI) is an OCI-compliant container base OS image with runtime and language support that can be used as the base for Docker images and Podman/Buildah images.
These will allow you to deploy and build supportable applications on Red Hat OpenShift and RHEL.
It also includes a number of additional user-space packages over a base UBI.
Read more about this <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/25/introducing-the-red-hat-build-of-the-openjdk-universal-base-images-now-in-red-hat-enterprise-linux-8-2/">over at Red Hat Developers</a>.</p>
<p>If you have been following, you’ll know the Infinispan team has been hard at work on Infinispan 11.
They are proud to announce that <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/06/15/infinispan-11/">Inifinspan 11.0.0. Final has been released</a>!
A number of improvements and features have been added to this release including clustering, CLI, Hot Rod Client improvements, non-blocking internals, and others.</p>
<p>Along with that new Infinispan release, you can now deploy a <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/06/16/native-server-announce/">natively compiled version of the Infinispan server</a>!
The memory footprint is only 286MB.
There are also native Quarkus extensions for your Quarkus based applications.</p>
<p>Not to be left out of the cloud native party, Apache Camel is <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/18/camel-k-1-0-the-serverless-integration-platform-goes-ga/">announcing the GA release of Apache Camel K 1.0</a>.
This release includes tooling, connectors, and integrations with Knative.
This is a great step forward for doing integrations with a small footprint.</p>
<p>Lastly, <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/17/red-hat-jboss-enterprise-application-platform-expansion-pack-1-0-released/">Red Hat JBoss Enterprise Application Platform Expansion Pack 1.0</a> was recently released.
This is a patch that adds MicroProfile capabilities to JBoss EAP.
There are some policy changes you will need to be aware of, but you find links to all of thosewithin the announcement.</p>
<p>Thanks again for being with us on another JBoss Editorial!</p>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/jason-porter.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Jason Porter</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Porter</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/jason-porter</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="data grid" term="data grid"/>
        <category label="camel" term="camel"/>
        <category label="editorial" term="editorial"/>
        <category label="" term=""/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss - 11 June 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-06-11.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-06-11.html"/>
        <updated>2020-06-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="quarkus, kogito, sso, infinispan">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss - 11 June 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome to another edition of the JBoss Editorial where we gather news from our communities and explore developments from our projects.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_mandrel">Mandrel</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>There has been some exciting
<a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/05/mandrel-a-community-distribution-of-graalvm-for-the-red-hat-build-of-quarkus/">news about Mandrel</a>.
You’ve likely heard of this by now but, in his announcement post, Mark explains how Red Hat has worked
with the GraalVM community to create a distribution of OpenJDK with GraalVM’s native-image
capabilities for producing native executables.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_ai_vs_covid_19">AI vs COVID-19</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2020/06/09/ai-vs-covid-19-how-java-helps-nurses-and-doctors-in-this-fight/">A recent DevNation Tech Talk</a> with
a very topical subject looks at how OptaPlanner has helped keep medical staff and patients safer with advanced planning algorithms.
It’s nice to see Java play a role in improving things for those who are at the front lines of the pandemic.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_in_the_community">In the Community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Eric Schnabell keeps his Cloud-native development series going with a look at
<a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/06/cloud-native-development-on-remote-containers.html">example use cases for using remote container platforms as development environments</a>.</p>
<p>The Infinispan blog has seen a flurry of activity in the run up to the 11.0.0.Final release, which
should be available real soon now. In the meantime, you can read about some of the things that will be
available in Infinispan 11 here:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>William Burns <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/06/09/offheap-resize/">shares some enhancements to Infinispan’s Off Heap implementation</a>
that simplify configuration and improve performance.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Pedro Ruivo <a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/06/05/xsite-improvements/">explains how Infinispan uses vector clocks</a>
to detect conflicts with asynchronous cross-site replication as well as the strategy for resolving conflicts.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>Over at the Strimzi blog, there is <a href="https://strimzi.io/blog/2020/06/09/mirror-maker-2-eventhub/">another installment of the series around Mirror Maker</a>.
Check out the post for mirroring to Azure Event Hub using Mirror Maker 2.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_release_roundup">Release Roundup</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-5-final-released/">Quarkus 1.5.0.Final has arrived</a>, which brings a fast-jar packaging format along with several new extensions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://wildfly.org/news/2020/06/08/WildFly20-Final-Released/">WildFly 20 has been released</a> with numerous bug fixes and updates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2020/06/keycloak-1002-released.html">Keycloak 10.0.2 is here</a>. Read all about it.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>That’s it for this week’s editorial. Thanks for reading and see you next time.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/don-naro.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Don Naro</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Don Naro</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/don-naro</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
        <category label="sso" term="sso"/>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JBoss Weekly Editorial 29 May 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-05-29.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-05-29.html"/>
        <updated>2020-05-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="infinispan, teiid, quarkus">
      <h1>JBoss Weekly Editorial 29 May 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>Welcome back!
Things keep rolling along for us within Middleware at Red Hat.
We have a couple of new releases and some blogs to talk about this week, so let’s dig in.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases">Releases</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/05/25/infinispan-11/">Infinispan 11.0.0.0.CR1</a> - This CR release sees non-blocking internal changes, a non-blocking Store SPI, slight modifications to clustering scaling, better/more server security, CLI, kubernetes/OpenShift operator, and an update to documentation!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/quarkusio/quarkus/milestone/68?closed=1">Quarkus 1.5.0.Final</a> - The milestoe is done and the artifacts are in Maven Central. There are a few things left to do to offically announce the release, but all the coding is done. The link here is to the GitHub milestone for a list of issues completed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://teiid.blogspot.com/2020/05/teiid-spring-boot-150-released.html">Teiid Spring Boot 1.5.0</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_blogs">Blogs</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>To go along with the Infinispan release, a couple of new blog posts have come out:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/05/28/cli/">CLI enhancements</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infinispan.org/blog/2020/05/26/hotrod-uri/">Hot Rod URI</a>, so you can connect via Hot Rod the same way you would a JDBC datastore.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>Eric Schabell has a couple of entries into his Cloud-native development series:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/05/cloud-native-development-a-blueprint.html">A Blueprint</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/05/cloud-native-development-common-architectural-elements.html">Common Architectural Elements</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>There is also an entry called <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/05/reality-bites-3-misconceptions-can-lead-to-micorservice-mayhem-slides.html">Reality Bites: 3 misconceptions that can lead to microservice mayhem</a> discussing pitfalls to avoid while working with Microservices</p>
<p>Lastly, we want to cover episodes 2, 3, and 4 of the Quarkus Insights video podcast.
Episode 2 covers <code>quarkus:dev</code> and Command mode.
Episode 3 discusses Hibernate and Panache.
The most recent one, episode 4, talks about JHipster for Quarkus.
You can find these video pod casts at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLsM3ZE5tGAVZ5p_CTx5YPLdMbyjlzfj8y">YouTube</a> or the audio on Apple Podcasts and Spotify.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/jason-porter.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Jason Porter</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Porter</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/jason-porter</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="infinispan" term="infinispan"/>
        <category label="teiid" term="teiid"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JBoss Weekly Editorial 14 May 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-05-14.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-05-14.html"/>
        <updated>2020-05-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="event-driven, codeready-containers, keycloak, devnation">
      <h1>JBoss Weekly Editorial 14 May 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><p>We’re a little light on the news this time, but those of us who have been reading the editorial for a few years will be familiar with the "after Summit slump."
With Red Hat Summit behind us (and what a great Summit, check out the sessions on demand if you missed them), many people have taken PTO.
Expect all the news, blogs, releases, etc. to pick back up in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>All that being said, we do have some blogs to go over and one release.</p><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_blogs">Blogs</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>First up is Eric Schabell’s second entry in his "Demystifying the Event Driven Architecture - Making the case" series.
You can read more about it <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/05/demystifying-event-driven-architecture-making-the-case.html">at his blog</a>.</p>
<p>We have another post by Eric: <a href="https://www.schabell.org/2020/05/code-ready-containers-installing-hr-employee-rewards-project.html">Code Ready Containers - Installing an HR employee rewards project using developer container catalog</a>.
For more information about CodeReady Containers, please visit the <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/products/codeready-containers/overview">Red Hat Developer page</a>.</p>
<p>There are a number of DevNation Tech Talks and master courses dropping within the next week, please visit the <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/devnation/">DevNation page</a> for more information.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_releases">Releases</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>Keycloak released a new version: <a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2020/05/keycloak-1001-released.html">Keycloak 10.0.1</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/jason-porter.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Jason Porter</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Porter</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/jason-porter</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="event-driven" term="event-driven"/>
        <category label="codeready-containers" term="codeready-containers"/>
        <category label="keycloak" term="keycloak"/>
        <category label="devnation" term="devnation"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in JBoss: 1 May 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-05-01.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.jboss.org/posts/weekly-2020-05-01.html"/>
        <updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <article class="" data-tags="summit, virtual, quarkus, kogito">
      <h1>This Week in JBoss: 1 May 2020</h1>
      
    <p class="preamble"></p><div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<a class="image" href="https://www.redhat.com/en/summit"><img src="/img/posts/rh-summit-banner.png" alt="rh summit banner"></a>
</div>
</div><p></p>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_2020_04_30_the_virtual_red_hat_summit_week">[2020-04-30] - The Virtual Red Hat Summit week</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<p>I’m writing this as we wrap up another successful Red Hat Summit.
But this year, with a significant distinction: the event was 100%
virtual. Despite the involuntary move to virtual, there were many
benefits that came about from the change in format. The event was
completely free, and of course required no travel, allowing a much
broader and more diverse set of attendees to benefit from the
content and experience. It was also ran in three regions to
accommodate many more timezones.</p>
<p>Being Red Hat we were keen to experiment with the format and find
new ways to engage with the community. It was important for us to
carry over as much of the personality and intimacy of the physical
event as possible. So, this needed to be more than just a bunch of
streamed talks. The talks were pre-recorded which allowed the
presenter(s) to participate directly in the Q&amp;A in real-time
as the talk proceeded. There was also a variety of sessions that
went beyond the talk format. For examples see
<em>Ask the experts</em>, <em>Networking social hour</em>, and
the <em>Virtual Open Neighborhood</em> on the
<a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/summit/agenda/agenda-at-a-glance">agenda</a>.</p>
<p>If you weren’t able to attend, or want to catch some of the
talks you missed, you can <a href="https://onlinexperiences.com/Launch/QReg.htm?ShowUUID=4245E6E3-7D25-496D-9B08-4CBDC87CCE74">re-live the virtual event here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>In other news…​</strong></p>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_quarkus_insights_on_youtube_live">Quarkus Insights on Youtube live</h3>
<p>This week Max Andersen and Emmanuel Bernard <a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/insights/">kicked off a new video/podcast series</a>
bringing insights into Quarkus. Each episode will focus on a
guest speaker discussing the development or usage of Quarkus.
There are also some dedicated Q&amp;A sessions planned. Be sure
to subscribe to the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/quarkusio">Quarkus YouTube channel</a>
to catch these sessions and other exciting Quarkus content.
In particular <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OCPFdpvL1Q0&amp;feature=youtu.be">join them on the 4th of May</a>
where Georgios Andrianakis will talk about Quarkus testing
and specifically the new mocking improvements in the recently
released Quarkus 1.4.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_kogito_a_modular_codegen_design_proposal">Kogito: A Modular Codegen Design Proposal</h3>
<p>In <a href="https://planet.jboss.org/post/kogito_a_modular_codegen_design_proposal">this post</a>
Edoardo Vacchi explains how Kogito is improving performance
by moving processing out of the run-time and into build-time.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_red_hat_summit_2020_ask_the_experts_hybrid_multicloud_pitfalls">Red Hat Summit 2020 - Ask the Experts: Hybrid Multicloud Pitfalls</h3>
<p>In one of the many <em>Ask the Experts</em> sessions,
Eric Schabell &amp; Roel Hodzelmans focused on their hybrid
multi-cloud pitfall theories. You can
<a href="https://planet.jboss.org/post/red_hat_summit_2020_ask_the_experts_hybrid_multicloud_pitfalls_slides">view the slides here</a>,
or <a href="https://onlinexperiences.com/Launch/QReg.htm?ShowUUID=4245E6E3-7D25-496D-9B08-4CBDC87CCE74">register for the Red Hat Summit Virtual event</a>
to re-watch the content on demand.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_free_book_on_knative_covering_camel_k_and_kafka_and_upcoming_webinar_with_live_demos">Free book on Knative covering Camel K and Kafka and upcoming webinar with live demos</h3>
<p>In this post Claus Ibsen <a href="https://planet.jboss.org/post/free_book_on_knative_covering_camel_k_and_kafka_and_upcoming_webinar_with_live_demos">alerts us to the free eBook</a>
written by Burr Sutter &amp; Kamesh Sampath on the subject of Knative. Go get your
free copy <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/books/knative-cookbook/">here</a>!</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_red_hat_summit_2020_business_automation_sessions">Red Hat Summit 2020 - Business Automation Sessions</h3>
<p>If you are interested in the area of <em>Business Automation</em>, be sure to view Kris
Verlaenen’s <a href="https://planet.jboss.org/post/virtual_red_hat_summit_2020_april_28_29">helpful summary</a>
of all the BI related talks held at Red Hat Summit.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_demystifying_the_event_driven_architecture_an_introduction_part_1">Demystifying the Event Driven Architecture - An introduction (part 1)</h3>
<p>Eric Schabell has <a href="https://planet.jboss.org/post/demystifying_the_event_driven_architecture_an_introduction_part_1">started a new blog series</a>
that explores the world of Event Driven Architectures (EDA).</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_six_reasons_why_you_will_love_camel_k">Six reasons why you will love Camel K</h3>
<p>Interested in Camel K, or want to find out what all the fuss is about?
<a href="https://planet.jboss.org/post/six_reasons_why_you_will_love_camel_k">Read on</a>,
and Christina will give you six reasons to love Camel K.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_hybrid_clouds_with_jgroups_and_skupper">Hybrid clouds with JGroups and Skupper</h3>
<p>Bela Ban follows up on his post explaining how to
<a href="http://belaban.blogspot.com/2019/12/spanning-jgroups-kubernetes-based.html">span JGroups Kubernetes-based clusters across Google and Amazon clouds</a>.
In <a href="https://planet.jboss.org/post/hybrid_clouds_with_jgroups_and_skupper">this new post</a>
Bela improves on the process by using <a href="https://skupper.io/">Skupper</a> to simplify this
task and encrypt the data exchanged between different clouds.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_this_weeks_releases">This Week’s Releases</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://quarkus.io/blog/quarkus-1-4-final-released/">Quarkus 1.4</a>. Command mode, HTTP 2, New FaaS framework, Mocking, and more.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.keycloak.org//2020/04/keycloak-1000-released.html">Keycloak 10.0.0</a>.
With <em>Identity Brokering Sync Mode</em>, <em>Client Session Timeout for OpenID Connect / OAuth 2.0</em>
and much more.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://planet.jboss.org/post/kogito_0_9_1_released">Kogito 0.9.1</a>. This release
is a bug fix release, but there has also been considerable work spent on
documentation and code examples. See the link for detais.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
      
      <div class="author">
        <pfe-avatar pfe-shape="circle" pfe-pattern="squares" pfe-src="/img/people/paul-robinson.png"></pfe-avatar>
        <span>Paul Robinson</span>
    
      </div></article>
  ]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robinson</name>
            <email>do-not-reply@jboss.com</email>
            <uri>https://www.jboss.org/people/paul-robinson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="summit" term="summit"/>
        <category label="virtual" term="virtual"/>
        <category label="quarkus" term="quarkus"/>
        <category label="kogito" term="kogito"/>
    </entry>
</feed>